(1996年)
《勇敢者的游戏：决战丛林》
嘿 哥们
Hey, kiddo.
- 什么 -  我发现点东西
- What? -  I found something.
你快来看看
You gotta check this out.
尤曼吉
"Jumanji."
棋盘游戏吗
Board game?
谁还玩棋盘游戏啊
Who plays board games?
双拳 双拳
Parry. Parry.
砰
Evade. Blam.
上钩拳
Uppercut.
好极了 你死了
Head slam. You're dead.
我左一拳 又一拳 反手勾拳 爆头
Strike. Strike. Counterstrike. Head slam.
准备 开打
Get ready. Fight.
我搞定了
I got it.
本杰明 富兰克林 这种
"...Benjamin Franklin,
国家例外论
"and it was this sense of national exceptionalism
使得西进运动的星星之火成燎原之势
that fueled the spreading wildfire of westward expansion."
斯宾塞 我进来了
Spencer? Honey?
啊 妈妈 上次不是说了吗 先敲门再进来
Aah! Mom, what did we say about the knocking?
我上班要迟到了 你放学后直接去你爸爸那里吗
I'm late for work. You going to your father's after school?
- 可能吧 -  别忘记带上肾上腺素
- Yeah, probably. -  Don't forget your EpiPen.
另外 别忘记 世间险恶
Please, remember, the world is terrifying.
千万注意安全
Be careful of everything.
我爱你甚于自己的生命 拜拜
I love you more than life itself. Bye.
-  周日晚上见 -  好的
- See you Sunday night. -  Okay.
- 我要迟了 妈妈 -  吃点东西再走
- Later, Mama. -  Eat something.
不行 我和斯宾塞约好了
I can't. I gotta go meet Spencer.
- 斯宾塞·吉尔平 -  是的 斯宾塞·吉尔平
- Spencer Gilpin? -  Yeah, Spencer Gilpin.
他在辅导我
He's, uh... He's been tutoring me.
- 帮我提高成绩 -  听到这个很高兴
- He's helping get my grades up. -  I love to hear that.
- 这个斯宾塞·吉尔平 -  真是不错啊
- Little Spencer Gilpin. -  Yeah.
- 你的成绩能提上去么 -  妈妈 肯定会有帮助的
- Your grades gonna be okay? -  That's why I'm getting help.
我就怕你会被踢出足球队
I'd hate for you to get dropped from the team...
不会发生这种情况的
I'm not gonna get dropped from the team.
会好起来的
It's... It's gonna be fine. Okay?
真可爱 是吧
That's cute, right?
好极了
Yeah.
- 唷 -  嗨 大冰箱
- Yo. -  Hey, Fridge.
你穿雨衣干嘛
Why you wearing a raincoat?
- 你什么意思 -  我是说 这又没有下雨 你穿什么雨衣
- What do you mean? -  I mean, it's not raining.
噢 这个嘛 我是觉得
Oh, well, it might.
你又不知道什么时候会下雨
I mean, you never know what's gonna happen.
- 啊 -  搞什么鬼 伙计
- Oy vey. -  What the hell, man?
不介意的话 我们长话短说吧
Do you mind? Can we speed this up?
这房子让我浑身不自在
Freak House makes me very uncomfortable.
给你
Here you go.
- 你都检查过了 -  是的
- You proofread everything? -  Yeah, I proofed it.
然后我写了个开头
And I gave it a beginning...
写了个结尾 中间也写了一些
and an ending and s-some in the middle.
伙计 要是我有时间 我肯定会自己写完的
I would've done it myself, if I had the time or whatever,
是 这不是什么大事
Yeah, it's no big deal.
嘿 我觉得 帮你写作业写论文什么的
Hey, man, I was thinking, so... I mean, it's been really fun,
也让我很开心
doing your papers and your homework and stuff,
不知道这个周末你要在做什么
but I don't know what you're doing this weekend.
- 但是我想 -  这周末 额
- I was thinking maybe we could... -  This weekend. Yeah, ah...
- 嗨 大冰箱 -  嗨
- Hey, Fridge. -  Hey.
要搭便车吗
You need a ride?
- 我要先走了 -  那个
- I'm going with her. -  You know what?
真是太巧了 我正好也有新安排了
That's actually better for me, scheduling-wise, too, so...
再见 大冰箱
See you later, Refrigerator.
抱歉 抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
嗨 美女
What up, girl?
随便吧
Whatever.
他看起来也不像是你最好的朋友
It's not like I was your best friend
你的童年一直都是这样
for your entire childhood.
- 没事的 -  你说什么
- That's fine. -  What'd you say?
额 没什么 先生
Uh, nothing, sir.
额 那个人超级奇怪
Oh, that guy is super weird.
那个可怜的男人
That poor man.
这些人真是太惨了
So awful what happened to those people.
我说的是那个男孩
I was talking about the kid.
你在这外面干什么呢
What are you doing out here?
我刚刚和我朋友说话呢
I was just talking to my friend.
闲逛也要找对地方
You should be more careful
你听到了吗
where you loiter, you hear me?
是的 弗里克先生 听到了
Yes, Mr. Vreeke. I hear you.
这个世界会吞噬你这样的孩子
This world swallows up kids like you.
我两个小时前上传的
It's been over two hours since I've posted,
但是他还没有评论 他甚至都没点个赞
and he hasn't commented. He hasn't even liked it.
- 我不.. 你也看到了? -  是的 美女
- You saw it. -  Yeah, gorge.
其实我也不知道他有什么问题
I don't know what his problem is.
谢谢 我也不是经常发动态
Thank you. It's not like I post all the time,
就想看看有没有人关注
just enough to stay relevant.
但是那照片已经是很可爱了..
But it's cute enough for Noah to...
嘿 你后面有个人盯着呢
Hey, there's some rando behind you.
- 嗨 -  嗨
- Hi. -  Hi.
贝瑟尼 你测验的时候在视频聊天?
Bethany, did you just make a call during a quiz?
是的 但是我已经写完了
Yeah. But I finished my quiz already.
哦 那你有注意到别的同学还在做题吗
Oh, okay. Well, have you noticed that other people haven't?
- 然后呢 -  哦 不好意思 我换个说法
- So? -  Oh, I'm sorry. Let me back up.
你应该能注意到 这世界上除了你 还有其他人的吧
You're aware there are other people in the world, right?
呃 我现在正在
Look, um, you know,
处理一些事情
I'm dealing with something right now,
相信我 现在我也很不爽
and I'm no happier about it than you are.
我现在有个麻烦事 露辛达
I'm having a crisis, and Lucinda, I mean,
我的这位好朋友在鼓励我呢
she's supporting me as a woman,
我觉得你也应该多鼓励我
and it feels like maybe you should too.
- 赶快挂掉电话 -  好的 马上就好
- Just hang up the phone. -  Okay, I'll wrap it up.
- 贝瑟尼 现在就挂掉 -  再聊2分钟就讲完了
- Bethany, hang it up now. -  Two minutes and we're done.
那就课后留校吧
And that's detention.
好 摆动你们的双臂
All right, keep those arms pumping.
动起来
Let's go!
贝瑟尼 你迟到了
Bethany, you're late.
对不起
Sorry.
我听说她和那个踢足球的分手了
I heard she broke up with that football guy.
那你就有机会追她了 哥们
This could be your opening, Fussfeld.
好了 现在我们
We're gonna practice
练习接球和投掷
catching and throwing.
两人一组 拿上球 动起来
So partner up and grab a football. Let's move!
嘿 玛莎
Hey, Martha.
玛莎 你一个人练不了接球
Martha. You can't play catch by yourself.
快点去组队
Pair up.
快 快去
Come on. Let's go.
不 不用了 我挺好的
No. No, I'm good.
好吧
Okay.
你必须像其他同学那样参与进来
You have to participate just like everybody else.
不然你来这里干嘛
Otherwise, why are you even here?
这是门必修课
It's a requirement.
- 玛莎 -  我觉得这毫无意义
- Martha... -  I think it's pointless.
体育课不会帮助我进入普林斯顿大学
Gym class is not gonna get me into Princeton,
而且我也不太了解 那种进球之后
and I don't understand the obsession with throwing
疯狂呐喊的人 噢 触地得分 5分
a ball into a hoop and, "Touchdown, five points!"
你说的太离谱了 但 首先
Okay. There's a lot wrong with that, but first of all...
这是体育锻炼 对你的身体有好处
It's physical activity, which is good for you.
有助于你同别人交流 这对你也是有好处的
With other people, also good for you.
如果你试一试 也许会体验到乐趣呢
And if you try it, you might even have some fun.
乐趣 就是为了这个么 为了乐趣
Fun. That's what we're doing here? Fun?
这里是学校
This is school.
我们来这是为了学习更有用的东西
We are supposed to be learning things that matter.
- 好吧 -  我们一生没有多少时间可以浪费
- Okay, Martha... -  We don't have
而且我也不想虚度年华
a lot of time in this life, and I personally
以后当一个体育老师
don't wanna waste it on being, like, a gym teacher.
- 我说错了 -  是的 你当然说错了
- That... That came out wrong. -  Yeah, it sure did.
你课后留校
That's detention.
嘴挺硬啊
That was hard-core.
是啊
Badass.
斯宾塞·吉尔平
Spencer Gilpin?
坐吧 斯宾塞
Have a seat, Spencer.
马瑟斯老师
Miss Mathers?
这种国家例外论
"And it was this sense of national exceptionalism
使得西进运动的星星之火成燎原之势
that fueled the spreading wildfire of westward expansion."
这话是不是挺耳熟 吉尔平先生
Does that sound familiar, Mr. Gilpin?
- 没有啊 -  这是安东尼关于
- It does not. -  It's the last sentence
西进运动论文的最后一句
of Anthony's paper on westward expansion.
巧合的是 这跟你去年在韦勃教授课上写的
And, coincidentally, it's the last sentence
西进运动论文的最后一句话一模一样
of your paper on westward expansion from last year.
真有意思
That's interesting.
是吗
Is it?
我觉得是的 我的意思是 竟然会这么巧
I think so. I mean, what are the odds of that?
是啊
Slim.
你在文章中多次使用了这个"燎原之火"
Yeah, you also used the same metaphor:
这个暗喻 比如
"The spreading wildfire," in your papers
在波士顿倾茶事件的论文 葛底斯堡战役的论文 以及
on the Boston Tea Party, the Battle of Gettysburg,
妇女选举权运动的论文中都有这句
and the women's suffrage movement.
这个用法本来就很普遍嘛
It's so hot in this room.
安东尼 我知道你很想通过我这门课
Anthony, I know how much you need to pass my class,
可你不能帮他写论文
but this is not how you do it.
- 我不会容忍作弊的 -  作弊
- I will not tolerate cheating. -  Cheating?
我没有作弊
I didn't... I didn't... I didn't cheat.
这都是我的错
It was my fault.
我让他这样干的
I made him do it.
你让他 找你替他写论文?
You made him... have you write his paper?
是的
Yeah.
我很抱歉 可以吗
Look. I'm sorry, okay?
不 不 这样是不行的
No, no, it's not okay.
天哪 你搞得我差点被踢出足球队
What the hell, man? You got me kicked off the team.
是的 你搞得我差点被开除呢
Yeah, well, you could've gotten me expelled.
现在大祸临头的不止你一个吧
It's not like you're the only one who's living dangerously.
- 大祸临头? -  是的
- Living dangerously? -  Yes.
我长这么大从来没冒过险
This is the most dangerous thing I've ever done in my life.
现在我要付出代价了
And now look at me. I'm paying the price.
那么..
Well...
这里挺热闹的啊
isn't this a fun group?
欢迎留校
Welcome to detention.
怎么了 斯宾塞
Yes, Spencer?
我只是想说我很抱歉
I wanna say that I'm sorry.
- 谢谢 -  本特利校长 我只是打了个电话而已
- Thank you. -  Bentley, all I did was make...
贝瑟尼 你们留校 都是有原因的
Bethany, please. You're all here for a reason.
你们心里清楚的
You know what it is.
现在你们应该想想
But this is what you should be thinking about:
你是谁
Who you are...
现在就好好想想
in this moment in time,
你想要成为什么样的人
and who you want to be.
你的一生如何度过
You get one life.
由你自己做主
You decide how you're gonna spend it.
幸运的是
Fortunately...
留校查看处 是最适合你们
there is no better place for self-reflection
自我反省的地方了
than detention.
站起来 各位 我们走
Get up, everybody. Let's go.
这里要改造成新的电脑室
We are turning this into a new computer center.
但在改造之前 要打扫干净
But before we do, it has to be cleaned out.
所有这些旧杂志 都要运到废品回收站
These old magazines are bound for the recycling plant.
但在回收之前都要整理好
But they have to be prepped before they go.
这些杂志上的订书钉都要卸下来
It seems all the staples must be removed.
如果你们今天做不完的话 明天接着做
Whatever you don't finish today, you finish tomorrow.
- 明天是周六 -  就因为我不想踢足球
- Tomorrow's Saturday. -  Because I wouldn't play?
- 我觉得这是不可能的 -  对
- I don't think that'll work. -  That's fair.
- 闭嘴 -  我建议你们快点开工吧
- Shut up. -  So I suggest you get started.
这是你们的工具
Choose your weapons.
嘿 他们在这放个保龄球干什么
Hey, what the hell they need with a bowling ball?
啊 不是吧 没有信号
Seriously, no reception?
- 今天还能更糟吗 -  你要来帮忙吗
- Okay, can today get any worse? -  Are you gonna help?
靠着漂亮脸蛋就能把活干完么
Or are you too pretty?
我就是靠脸啊
I'm too pretty.
嗨 我今天看到你和韦勃教练谈话了
Hey. I was watching you with Coach Web today.
我不是故意看你的
I wasn't watching you, I wasn't...
不是那种偷窥之类的
Not, like, in a weird way. I just...
我只是 正好在那里 我们上同一节课
I was in the room. We're in the same class.
嗯 但是我觉得你说的关于体育课
Um, but I thought you were saying some really smart things
还有其它课的观点很不错
about why P.E. sucks and, um...
挺棒的
about other subjects.
谢谢
Thanks.
嗯
Yeah.
嘿 这是什么
Yo. What's this?
- 我不知道 -  这像不像某种
- I don't know. -  What is it, like,
老式的任天堂游戏机
some type of old-school Nintendo or something?
我觉得不是
I don't think so.
我认不出来
I don't recognize it.
梦幻世界很神秘
"A game for those who seek to find...
来玩勇敢者游戏
"a way to leave their world behind.
尤曼吉
Jumanji."
大家干活了 拔钉子
Staples, people. Staples.
尤曼吉 是什么意思
"Jumanji"? What does that mean?
我也不知道 从来没听说过这个
I have no idea. Never heard of it.
我该选哪个角色
Uh, which one do I pick?
我不知道 我觉得无所谓的
I don't know. I don't think it matters that much.
飞行家 杰斐逊·麦克多诺
"Jefferson 'Seaplane' McDonough.
流氓飞行员
Pilot and rascal."
- 这个选不了 -  那换一个试试
- It's not working. -  Okay, try another one.
毛子 富兰克林·芬巴
"Franklin 'Moose' Finbar."
这名字听起来就很厉害
He sounds like a badass.
他还是一个动物学专家 这太酷了
And he's a zoology expert, which is awesome.
- 到你选 -  好
- You pick. -  Okay.
斯莫德·勇石博士
"Dr. Smolder Bravestone."
贝瑟尼 你玩吗
Bethany, you in?
好吧
Fine.
那我选
I'll be...
谢利·奥布伦
Shelly Oberon...
身材火辣的天才
the curvy genius.
嘿 书呆子 来吧 到你了
Hey, yo, Staples, come on. It's your turn.
不了
Uh, no.
- 我不玩 谢谢 -  别嘛 就玩几分钟
- No, thanks. -  Wait. Just for a few minutes?
这肯定挺有乐趣
It'll be fun.
她可不喜欢乐趣
She's not big on fun.
好吧 我玩
Okay. Fine.
这也许是我做过的最傻的事了
This may be the lamest thing I've ever done.
我可不敢苟同
I highly doubt that.
欢迎来到尤曼吉
Welcome to Jumanji!
现在是什么情况
What's going on?
我觉得这是短路了
I think it's shorting out.
快拔插头
Unplug it!
发生了什么 你的手怎么了
What's going on? What's happening to your hands?
- 你这是怎么回事 -  我不知道
- What's wrong with you? -  I don't know.
斯宾塞
Spencer!
噢不 我的天哪
Oh, my God!
这是搞什么
What the hell, man?
噢不
Oh, no.
该死的
Holy shit...
各位
Guys?
你们在哪 我声音不是这样的
Guys? Why do I sound like this?
我的头发呢
Where's my hair?
搞什么
What the...
我的天
Oh, God!
这是什么鬼情况
What kind of stupid-ass...
- 你是谁 -  你又是谁
- Who are you? -  Who are you?
她是谁
Who is she?
那你们又是谁
Who are you guys? Huh?
好吧 这是什么
Okay, what the hell?
- 我的天 -  我的天
- God! -  Oh, my God!
- 快走开 -  我要投诉...
- Get off of me! -  I am suing...
- 我的声音怎么了 -  别压着我
- What's wrong with my voice? -  Get off of me!
- 我在哪 -  你压着我了 走开
- Where am I? -  You're crushing me! Get off!
走开
Get...
搞什么 我身体的其他部分呢
What the hell? What happened to the rest of me?
那是什么 我这是背了什么东西
What is this? What is this on my back?
那到底是什么
What is this?
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
大冰箱
Fridge?
没错 我是大冰箱 你是谁
Yeah, I'm Fridge. Who are you?
我是斯宾塞
I'm Spencer.
什么 别扯了 现在是什么情况
What? The hell you are. What is going on? Huh?
我觉得
I think...
我们在游戏里了
we're in the game.
- 不好意思 你再说一遍 -  你在说什么
- Sorry, excuse me? -  What are you talking about?
不知怎么搞的 我觉得我们
Somehow, I don't know how...
我们好像被吸进游戏里了
I think we got, like, sucked into the game.
然后我们就变成了我们选的角色
And we've become the avatars that we chose.
所以 我是斯宾塞 但我的长相还有嗓音
So it's me, Spencer, but yet I look and sound...
就是斯莫德·勇石博士
like Dr. Smolder Bravestone.
你是说 你是斯宾塞
You're telling me that you're Spencer?
是的是的 没错
Yes, yes, yes. That's it.
大冰箱 我是斯宾塞 这就意味着你是毛子芬巴
Fridge, I'm Spencer. Which means you're Moose Finbar.
你马甲上写着呢 然后
It says it right there on your vest. And...
- 玛莎 -  没错
- Martha? -  Yeah.
你是铁拳萝比
You're Ruby Roundhouse.
还有贝瑟尼 你是谢利·奥布伦教授
And, Bethany, you're Professor Shelly Oberon.
只不过谢利大概是谢尔顿的简称
Only Shelly must be short for Sheldon.
你在说些什么
What are you talking about?
我的天哪 他说得没错
Oh, my God. Oh, my God, he's right.
那你
And you...
你是斯宾塞 这个你吗
you're Spencer? You?
没错 大家 我都说了
Yes. Guys, I'm telling you.
我是斯宾塞 我是斯宾塞
I am Spencer. I'm... Aah!
没错 那就是斯宾塞
Yep, that's Spencer.
这么说 我
So that means I...
我是
I'm...
等等 贝瑟尼 贝瑟尼 别去
Wait, Bethany. Bethany, don't!
不
No!
我是一个肥胖的中年男人
I'm an overweight, middle-aged man.
我有个文身 我妈一直告诉我
Uh, I have a tattoo.
要是我去纹文身 她就要把我杀了
My mom always said she'd kill me if I ever got a tattoo.
这是什么
What is this?
我也有一个文身
I have one too.
若隐若现
Sometimes.
慢着
Wait a second.
我的手机呢
Where's my phone?
为什么我要在丛林里穿着这一身
Why am I wearing this outfit in a jungle?
超短裤和皮革的露脐装
Tiny, little shorts and a leather halter top.
这一身衣服搞什么鬼
I mean, what is this?
我还成了花园里的一个活侏儒呢 我的手机呢
I look like a living garden gnome. Where is my phone?
- 谁管你 -  我们都附在别人身上了
- Who cares? -  We are in different bodies!
找手机似乎不是 现在最紧急的问题
It doesn't seem like the most pressing concern at this moment.
是吗 你不觉得现在应该
Really? You don't think
去打个电话么
this would be a good moment to make a call
给别人发消息 或者把你的状态
or text somebody or change your status
改成 困在一个该死的电子游戏里 吗
to "stuck in a video game"?
我的意思是 我身上没带我的抗过敏药
All I'm saying is, I don't have my Claritin, okay?
而且我几乎对所有东西过敏
And I'm allergic to almost everything.
天哪
Oh, no.
你过敏啊 斯宾塞
You got allergies, Spencer? Huh?
好惨哦 我还矮了两英尺呢
I don't have the top two feet of my body!
大家 这一切一定不是真的
You guys, this can't actually be happening.
也许我们都昏迷了
Maybe we're all in a coma.
所有人 我们所有人一起昏迷了吗
Together? We're all in a coma together?
这是唯一的解释了 那个旧游戏机
It's the only explanation. That old game machine
一定是让我们触电了 现在
must have electrocuted us, and now we're...
- 我的天 贝瑟尼 -  我的天
- Oh, my God, Bethany! -  Oh, my God, oh, my God!
我的天啊 你最好下去救她
Oh, my God! You better get in there and go save her.
我才不要下去 你去
I'm not getting in there! You get in.
我哪都不去 我背着包呢
I'm not going anywhere. I got a backpack on.
你不能带着背包下水 是个人都知道这道理
You don't get in water with a backpack. Everybody knows that.
搞什么
What the...
- 贝瑟尼 -  发生什么...
- Bethany! -  What just...
你还好吗
Are you okay?
那太刺激了
That was so intense.
我感觉 甚至无法动弹了
I, like, can't even with this place.
- 刚才发生了什么 -  一头犀牛把我吃了
- What just happened to you? -  I got eaten by a rhino,
然后我从几百米的高空掉了下来
and then I fell, like, a thousand feet from the sky.
没错 看起来是这么回事
Yeah, that's what it looked like.
那是河马 它们是杂食性动物
That was a hippo. They're omnivorous.
在陆地上跑起来像马一样快
They're fast as a horse over short distances,
咬合力达到八千一百牛顿
and they have the bite force of 8100 newtons.
我怎么会知道这些
How do I know this?
你是动物学专家
You're an expert in zoology.
- 什么 -  我还是一个胖胖的老男人是吧
- What? -  I'm still an old fat guy, right?
- 恐怕是这样 -  等等
- I'm afraid so. -  Wait.
你们怎么能这么淡定 我是说她从天上掉了下来
Why is everybody okay with this? I mean, she fell out of the sky.
那个 大家
Um, guys?
贝瑟尼 起来 贝瑟尼 快起来 起来啊
Bethany, get up. Bethany, get up. Get up!
快跑 快跑
Go, go, go!
勇石博士 欢迎来到尤曼吉
Ah! Dr. Bravestone! Welcome to Jumanji!
别傻站在那 快上车
Don't just stand there. In you go.
走走走 快走
Go, go, go.
勇石博士
Dr. Bravestone.
著名的考古学家和国际探险家
Famed archaeologist and international explorer.
你是一位有胆识的专家
Known across the seven continents
事迹传遍了七大洲
for your courageous exploits.
这有安全带吗
Is there a seat belt?
不得不说 见到你真是荣幸之至
I can't tell you what an honor it is to finally meet you.
说真的 我也不怕你笑话 你本人比我想象的更潇洒
I'm not embarrassed to say you're more dashing in person.
额 多谢
Um, thanks.
你是谁
Who are you?
奈吉尔·比林斯利为您服务
Nigel Billingsly at your service,
你是铁拳萝比 少男杀手
Ruby Roundhouse, killer of men.
欢迎来到尤曼吉
Welcome to Jumanji.
我在这恭候您多时了
I've been so anxious for your arrival.
各位都知道 尤曼吉处于生死存亡之际
As you know, Jumanji is in grave danger.
我们指望着你们四位能解除诅咒
We're counting on the four of you to lift the curse.
- 诅咒 -  什么诅咒
- Curse? -  What curse?
不好意思 你看到我的手机了吗
Excuse me. Have you seen my phone anywhere?
谢尔顿·奥布伦教授
Professor Sheldon Oberon.
欢迎来到尤曼吉
Welcome to Jumanji.
奈吉尔·比林斯利为您服务
Nigel Billingsly at your service.
我在这恭候您多时了
I've been so anxious for your arrival.
这人是怎么了
What's with this guy?
我觉得他是个NPC
I think he's an NPC.
是什么 说人话
A what? English, please.
一个非玩家角色 他是游戏里设定的
A non-player character. He's part of the game.
所以不管我们问了什么
So anything we ask him,
他都按照编好的程序回答
he only has his programmed series of responses.
明白了 现在都清楚了
Got it. It's all clear now.
耗子富兰克林·芬巴
Franklin "Mouse" Finbar.
欢迎来到尤曼吉
Welcome to Jumanji.
是毛子 不是耗子
It's Moose. It's not Mouse.
不是的 先生 我敢肯定是叫耗子
No, good sir. I'm quite sure it's Mouse.
- 耗子 -  就是因为您个子小
- Mouse? -  A nickname given
讨人喜欢 才有这个绰号的
for your diminutive stature and adorable manner.
我知道你肯定在这
I knew you'd be here.
勇石博士不管到哪
Dr. Bravestone doesn't go anywhere
都会带着他可靠的跟班
without his trusty sidekick.
跟班
Sidekick?
自从勇石博士在秘鲁丛林
Ever since Dr. Bravestone rescued you
把你从军阀手中解救出来后
from the clutches of a warlord
你就跟他形影不离
in the jungles of Peru, you've never left his side.
好吧
Right.
我们还是说说那个诅咒的事吧
Can we go back to the curse thing?
这都写在 我寄给你的信上了 勇石博士
It's all documented in the letter I sent you.
或许你应该大声读出来
Perhaps you should read it aloud.
我没有收到
I don't have a let...
好吧
Right, uh...
勇石博士 我写信来是为了告诉您
"Dr. Bravestone, I am writing to you
尤曼吉已经危在旦夕了
"regarding the desperate situation.
我们现在需要你的帮助
In Jumanji. We need your help at once."
- 哇 伙伴们 -  出什么事了
- Whoa... Guys? -  What's happening?
这到底是怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
我觉得这是一个过场动画 很多游戏中都有类似情节
It's a cut scene. A lot of games have them.
就是介绍故事背景的那种小片段
It's like a little movie to tell you the back-story.
我的名字叫奈吉尔·比林斯利
My name is Nigel Billingsly,
尤曼吉的向导
Jumanji field guide.
我曾受雇于你以前的搭档
I was hired by your former partner,
现在的死敌 罗素 范 佩尔特教授
now nemesis, Professor Russel Van Pelt
雇佣了一支忠诚的寻宝队
to lead a fateful expedition.
其实 范 佩尔特教授
You see, Professor Van Pelt
他曾经在寻找丛林里的美洲豹神像
had come in search of the fabled Jaguar Shrine,
神圣的尤曼吉宝石所藏之处
resting place of the sacred jewel of Jumanji.
你也知道
As you know better than anyone,
他对那宝石无比痴迷
the jewel was his great obsession.
经过多年的探索
And after years of research, he believed
他认为自己终于找到了宝石的所在地
that he had discovered its whereabouts.
真的吗
Could it be?
我终于找到了
Have I finally found it?
范·佩尔特告诉我 他找到宝石是为了用文字
Van Pelt told me that he wanted to find the jewel
记录下它的存在
in order to document it in his writings.
- 它是真的 -  可我万万没想到
- It's real! -  What I did not know
他其实是想把宝石占为己有
was that he intended to take the jewel for himself.
找到了
I found it.
我找到了
I found it!
根据传说 美洲豹神像一直守护着尤曼吉丛林
Legend tells that the Jaguar watches over Jumanji
谁取走神像的宝石之眼
and anyone who dares to blind him
谁就会被黑恶力量吞噬
will be consumed by a dark power.
范·佩尔特拥有操纵
Van Pelt assumed dominion
丛林中所有生物的能力
over all of Jumanji's creatures,
他能操控它们
possessing them, controlling them.
可怕的诅咒降临到了这片祥和的土地上
And a terrible curse befell this once-placid land.
我求他把宝石放回去
I begged him to put it back,
可他既然拿到了宝石
but once he had it in his grasp,
就决不会放手
he could never let it go.
那天夜里 我等他们都睡着了之后
So I waited till they slept that night,
就动手了
and I made my move.
去把我的宝石追回来
Bring me that jewel!
谁敢阻拦 格杀勿论
And slaughter anyone who tries to stop you.
宝石在此 给你
Right, then. Here you go.
你们要团结协作
With the invaluable help of your associates,
运用各自的技能
you must use your complementary skills
把宝石放回美洲豹神像的眼睛上
to return the jewel to the Jaguar's eye
然后解除诅咒
and lift the curse.
我相信你们肯定迫不及待跃跃欲试了
I'm sure you'll want to get started right away.
- 其实我 -  祝你好运
- Actually, I think... -  Good luck!
尤曼吉丛林的命运掌握在你们手中
The fate of Jumanji is in your hands.
- 什么 -  记住
- What? Oh... -  And remember:
游戏目标我解读
The goal for you, I'll recite in verse.
归还宝石 打破诅咒
Return the jewel and lift the curse.
欲回故乡 拯救丛林
If you wish to leave the game.
大喊一声尤曼吉
You must save Jumanji And call out its name.
祝你们好运 尤曼吉丛林的命运掌握在你们手中
Good luck! The fate of Jumanji is in your hands.
- 记住 游戏目标 -  他又开始重复了
- And remember: -  He's saying the same thing over.
游戏目标我解读
I'll recite in verse.
归还宝石 打破诅咒
Return the jewel and lift the curse.
欲回故乡 拯救丛林
If you wish to leave the game.
大喊一声尤曼吉
You must save Jumanji And call out its name.
没事的 你能搞定的 现实中你人见人爱
It's okay. You can handle this. In real life, people love you.
跟谁都能谈情说爱
You can hook up with anyone you want.
你害怕的时候就是这么安慰自己的吗
Is that what you tell yourself when you're scared?
你能不能消停一会儿 别对我冷嘲热讽了
Can you not judge me for two seconds?
我刚刚跟诺亚分手 还变成了个大叔
I split up with Noah, I turned into a guy,
连自己的手机都找不到 我难过一会儿不行吗
and I cannot find my phone. I am allowed to be upset.
勇石博士 这是丛林的地图
Dr. Bravestone, here's a map of Jumanji.
你得去集市找到缺失的那部分
You must go to the bazaar and find the missing piece.
- 集市 -  什么缺失的部分
- The bazaar. -  Missing piece of what?
- 再会 -  等等 就不能
- Cheerio! -  You can't give us a ride
- 开车直接送我们去神像那边吗 - 别忘了
- to the statue? -  And remember:
欲回故乡
If you wish to leave the game.
拯救丛林 大喊一声尤曼吉
You must save Jumanji And call out its name.
- 这个先放你包里 - 不好
- You want to, uh, put this in there? -  No.
拜托 冰箱 只有你 有背包
Come on, you're the only one with a backpack, Fridge.
然后呢 我们有一张地图
So what? We have a map.
现在要去找
So now we're supposed to go and find...
我想 是要找到集市吧
The bazaar, I guess?
所以 我们把宝石放回美洲豹神像
So we return the jewel to the Jaguar statue,
我们就可以回家了 没问题
and then we go home. No problem.
就不能直接离开吗
Why can't we just leave, stop the game,
不想玩这破游戏了
without doing all this stuff?
我们必须完成这个游戏
We have to finish the game.
我觉得
I think...
我们必须拯救丛林
I think we have to save Jumanji.
天哪 他可真有男人味
Damn, that is a man right there.
别哭 别哭 别哭
Don't cry, don't cry, don't cry.
Don't cry.
传染源可真多
There are so many diseases out here.
真够热的
It's hot.
好吧 这是我擅长的
Okay, this is what I'm good at.
玩电子游戏 这方面我算老手了
Playing video games. It's what I do.
实际上我每天都在玩游戏
It's literally the main thing that I do.
玩这样的电子游戏 肯定要闯关
Play a game like this, there'll be levels.
要想结束游戏 就要闯过所有关卡
In order to finish, you gotta complete all the levels.
随着游戏进行 关卡会越来越难
Levels are gonna get harder as we go along.
我们闯过了所有关卡之后
We complete the levels...
斯宾塞 你知道我们现在要去哪吗
Do you even know where we're going?
- 大概吧 - 大概？
- Kind of. -  Kind of?
那真是太棒了 我们有主心骨喽
Oh, that's good, then. We're in good hands.
我觉得缺失的部分
Okay, the missing piece, I'm guessing.
我知道了 缺的肯定就是这个
That must be what we're looking for,
地图缺了一部分
the missing piece of the map.
但问题是 上面并没有东西啊
The problem is, there's nothing here.
你说空白是什么意思 跟他说的一样 这是个地图
What do you mean? It's a map, just like he said.
尤曼吉丛林的地图
It's a map of Jumanji.
制图学
Cartography.
- 你说什么 -  就是研究地图的学科
- What's that? -  The study of maps.
这是奥伯伦教授的技能
It was one of Professor Oberon's skills.
没错
Yes. That's right.
哦 所以你们都看不到 只有我能
Oh, so you can't see this, but I can?
我们选的角色都有特定的技能
The characters we chose, we all have certain skills.
一定有办法可以让我们看到我们的技能
So there's gotta be a way to access our...
天哪
Oh!
哇天哪
Wow.
你是怎么做到的？
What'd you just do?
强项 无畏 攀爬
"Strengths: Fearless. Climbing.
速度 回旋镖
Speed. Boomerang.
深沉眼神杀
Smoldering intensity."
你这是在干什么？
What the hell are you doing?
- 刚刚怎么了 -  嗯 你刚才抛了一个深沉的眼神
- What just happened? -  Um, you just smoldered.
弱点
"Weakness...
无
None"?
怎么把这个列表弄出来的
How'd you do that? That, uh, list?
其实我只是 按了一下我强健的左胸肌
Well, I just... I think I just pressed my enormous left pec.
就是你胸部那里 我来告诉你怎么弄
It's like the boob area. Let me show you.
把你的脏手拿开！
Get away from me.
至少在我们面前做个示范吧
At least press it in front of us...
好让我们弄清楚到底怎么操作
...so we know exactly how...
强项 空手道 太极 合气道 战斗舞蹈
"Strengths: Karate. T'ai chi. Aikido. Dance fighting?"
战斗舞蹈 这也算强项
Dance fighting? Is that even a thing?
弱点
"Weakness:
毒液
Venom."
搞什么玩意
Seriously?
古生物学 那是什么
"Paleontology." What does that even mean?
研究化石的吧
Study of fossils, I think.
- 还挺酷的 -  空手道辣妹
- That's kind of cool. -  Says the gorgeous karate badass
居然觉得没有耐力 研究化石的老家伙挺酷
to the old fossil guy who doesn't have any endurance.
我讨厌这个游戏
I hate this game.
弱点 蛋糕
"Weakness: Cake."
是啊 我的弱点居然是蛋糕
Yes, cake is my weakness.
还有速度和力量
Along with speed and strength.
力量居然是我的弱点
Strength is my weakness.
我有个小问题
Hey, can I... Quick question.
力量怎么会是我的弱项
How is strength my weakness?
有人能解释一下吗 还有 我要速度干什么？
Somebody explain that to me. And why would I need speed?
为什么要跑得快呢 后面又不是有什么该死的斑马在追我
Why would I need to be fast when I'm being chased
还有这种愚蠢的帽子
by an enormous killer zebra or some shit in this dumb-ass hat?
你还是个不错的武器管家嘛
You're also a good weapons valet.
- 那什么意思 -  我觉得是说我的武器
- What does that mean? -  Well, I think it means
都在你的背包里
you carry my weapons in your backpack,
我需要的时候 你可以把武器递给我
and you give them to me when and if I need them?
伙计们 地图 有变化了
You guys. The map, it's changing.
你说什么
What do you mean?
- 地图上有什么 - 好吧
- What's it say? -  Okay, well,
其实信息量也不是很大
there's not a lot of information.
一分钟之前 地图上还没有这字 现在有了
But a minute ago, it didn't say this and now it does.
这里写着 咆哮谷
It says, "The Mighty Roar."
听起来不太妙
I don't like that.
- 我不说了 - 还有什么
- I'm done. -  What else?
好吧 这里写着 深渊沼泽
Okay. And right here, it says "From The Deep."
河马是从沼泽来的 没错 那些...
The hippo came from the deep. The one that...
别提那个了 接着说吧
Yes, the thing that did the thing. That's it. Moving on.
所以如果深渊沼泽是第一关
So if "From The Deep" is the first level,
那咆哮谷就是第二关
then "The Mighty Roar" must be the second level.
它在哪儿
Which way?
好吧
Okay.
如果那儿是那儿
If that is that...
这儿是这儿
and that is here...
这儿就是咆哮谷
Right here, I think.
这破游戏到底在搞什么
What is this game?
快跑
Run!
什么
Wait!
再快一些
Come on, legs!
我怎么跑得这么慢
Why am I running so slow?
快跑 天哪 天哪 天哪
Oh, my God, oh, my God, oh, my God!
这简直糟透了
Aah! This sucks!
我的天 我的天
Split up!
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
哇塞
Whoa.
快跑
Come on!
- 那些家伙火力太猛了 -  是么
- Those guys have huge guns. -  Oh, really?
斯宾塞 只是火力猛吗？
Is that what those are, Spencer?
- 让我看看你的包 - 看了干嘛
- Let me see your backpack. -  For what?
我的武器都在你的背包里
Inside your backpack, you have my weapons.
快趴下
Get down.
背包里有你的武器
Got your weapons?
我摸到一个 这是什么
I can't feel no... What's this?
太好了 回旋镖 这是我的技能之一
Oh, yes. Boomerang, it's one of my strengths.
你要怎么用它
What are you gonna do with it?
我不知道 大概是用来干掉他们吧
I don't know. Kill them, I guess.
就用这玩意儿？
Kill them with that?
你还有更好的办法吗
You got a better idea?
小心
Oh, watch yourself.
瞧着吧
Watch this.
- 干得不错啊 - 在那边
- Nice work. -  There!
你刚刚扔那一下
Want me to see if I got a hacky sack
真是屁用没有
for you to throw and do nothing with?
- 慢着 -  不
- Wait, wait. -  Oh, no.
成功了
It worked.
他们来了 快跑
Here they come. We gotta go.
我跑不过他们
I can't outrun those guys.
我们现在得快跑了
We gotta go now!
- 到我背上来 - 什么 不 那我宁愿死
- Get on my back. -  I would rather die.
- 快到我背上来 - 不 让我死吧
- Jump on my back! -  Nope. I'll die.
斯宾塞
Put me down!
放我下来
Spencer! Put me down!
开玩笑吧
You have got to be kidding me.
不不不不不
Oh, no, no, no!
- 我们得跳下去 - 你疯了吗
- We have to jump! -  Are you out of your mind?
只要不跳悬崖 你让我做什么都行
I would rather do anything else now but that.
跳
Jump!
- 玛莎 - 跳
- Martha! -  Jump!
我们得跳下去
We gotta jump!
我们都不知道水有多深
We don't know how deep that water is.
- 我们要快走了 -  不
- We gotta go! -  No, no!
- 听着 你必须要往下跳 - 不
- You gonna jump. Jump! -  No!
我觉得自己要得心脏病了
Oh! I think I'm having a coronary.
喘不过气来了
I'm having difficulty breathing.
我这辈子都没这么丢脸过
That was the most humiliating moment of my life.
你下次再敢背我试试
Don't you do that again.
我喝了不少水
I took in a lot of water.
他们打中我了
They got me.
噢不
Oh, no.
玛莎
Martha?
- 她怎么了 -  她死了吗 她是死了吗
- Wait, what just happened to her? -  Is she dead? Did she die?
等等
Wait a second.
到底发生了什么
What the hell is hap...
- 从我背上下去 -  你没事吧？
- Get off of my back! -  Are you okay?
- 应该吧 -  快下去
- I think so. -  Off of me!
- 我的天 快下去 -  我马上从你身上下来
- Goodness gracious, get off! -  I'm getting off of you.
怎么不问问我有没有事
Anybody care if I'm okay?
当我是人肉气垫吗
What am I, a human landing pad?
跟我想的一样
That's what I thought.
我们每个人手臂上的小纹身
We each have three lives, guys.
代表着我们每个人最开始有三条命
These little tattoos on our arms...
老天啊 这肌肉可真结实
Jesus, would you look at the size of that thing?
- 斯宾塞 - 什么
- Spencer! -  What?
- 你在说什么啊 -  这是我们的生命
- You were saying? -  It's our life count.
贝瑟尼之前被一只河马吞进了肚子 所以她现在只有两条杠了
Bethany got eaten by a hippo, so now she only has two lines.
他说得对
He's right.
等等 那如果我们用完了我们的生命怎么办
Wait. What happens if we use up all our lives?
那就意味着
Well, usually that would mean...
游戏结束
...game over.
你这话什么意思
What do you mean, "game over"?
是说我们真的会死在这里吗
Are you saying that we can actually die in here?
其实我也不太确定
I mean, I don't know for sure, but...
你不确定?
You're not sure? You're not sure,
- 你这种游戏天才说自己不确定？ -  我以前也没亲身进过游戏 好么?
- Mr. Video-Game-Genius? -  I've never been stuck in one!
所以我不是很确定 不过没错 我们恐怕都会死在这儿
So I'm not certain, but, yes, I'm afraid we all could die.
我现在最担心的就是这个
That is my big concern right now.
我们现在最好先找到地图上缺的那一块
We better find the missing piece, then.
好的
Okay.
翻过这座山后好像
It looks like there's a village
有一个村子
on the other side of this mountain.
那可能就是集市
Maybe that's the bazaar.
- 行动吧 -  等等
- Let's do it. -  Wait.
我想先撒个尿
I gotta take a leak first.
这事我担心了一整天
I've been dreading this all day,
但是我确实也很想上厕所
but so do I.
我能跟你一起去然后你教我怎么做吗
Can I come with you and you show me how it's done?
我需要你的帮助
I may need your help.
嗯 当然 我会帮你的
Uh, yeah, sure. Yeah, I'm... I'll help you out.
那 我们该怎么做
So how do we do this?
放轻松
Uh. Easy. You just, uh...
先把裤子拉链拉下来 把它拿出来 然后就可以了
You unzip, take it out, fire away.
记得瞄准 那非常重要
Remember to aim. It's very important.
我的天 我感觉就像那里真的
My God, you guys, there is literally a penis
长了一个小弟弟
attached to my body right now.
玛莎 过来看我的小弟弟啊
Martha, come look at my penis!
不用了 我谢谢你
No, thanks.
- 你这是第一次见到吗？ -  没错 我不是很想看到它
- This the first you've seen it? -  Yes. I didn't wanna look.
我来这的第一件事就是看它一眼
I looked at mine the first 20 seconds here.
幸好我那玩意儿
I'm happy to report that I was able
跟外面世界的一样
to bring one thing from the outside world.
你 你在做什么
Are you... What are you doing?
- 你在偷看吗 -  啊抱歉
- Are you looking? -  Sorry.
你不能往这看
You don't look over!
是的 不能看 这是规矩
Yeah, you never look. It's a thing.
好孩子
Okay, good boy.
我们现在慢慢的 来做这件事
We're gonna take this nice and slow,
不会有事的
and nobody's gonna get hurt.
- 现在该怎么做 -  尿出来
- Now what? -  Now blast off.
还有别忘了瞄准
And aim. Don't forget to aim.
你怎么跟瞄准杠上了
What is with you and aiming? What happened?
现在是扯这些的时候吗
Can we not talk about this?
哇 哇 哇
Wow, wow, wow!
现在容易多了
Oh, this is so much easier!
很酷对吧
It's cool, right?
是的 就像自己有一个手柄
Yeah, because you have, like, a handle.
我现在没把这件事拍下来分享出去
The fact that I'm not Instagramming this
真是太可惜了
right now is insane.
勇石博士来了
Bravestone.
还有他的队伍
Him and that whole lot.
他们逃走了
They got away?
我们在丛林里跟丢了
We lost them in the jungle.
我早该料到的
I should have known.
老大 你的意思是
H-how do you mean, sir?
我会召唤丛林里的每一个生物
I will summon every creature and every soldier
每一名士兵去追捕他们
to hunt them down.
夺回我的东西
Reclaim what is mine.
去找他们
Find them.
大家小心脚下
Be careful of the ground, guys.
地上坑坑洼洼的 我不想你们有人扭到脚
It's uneven. I'd hate for anybody to twist an ankle.
- 之前有次露营我就受伤了 -  你的嘴巴能歇会儿吗
- I did that once... -  Please stop talking?
好吧 没问题
Okay, sure. No problem.
- 我能借一下你的外套吗 - 当然可以
- Can I borrow your jacket? -  Yeah, sure.
- 谢谢 -  你要做什么
- Thanks. -  What are you doing?
感觉就像穿着比基尼上学
I feel like I'm wearing a bikini at school.
我以前干过这事 然后他们把我送到校长办公室去了
I did that once. They sent me to the office.
我前男友喜欢我穿得暴露一点
Noah likes it when I show some skin.
这样有助于增进感情
It's like the key to our relationship.
挑剔够了吗 说真的 我在你旁边都不敢开口了
Judgy much? Seriously, I can't even open my mouth around you.
你甚至都不了解我 可你好像打心眼里讨厌我
You don't even know me, but you, like, decided you hate me.
等等 我并不讨厌你
Oh, wait a minute. I don't hate you.
- 你不讨厌我吗 -  不讨厌
- You don't? -  No.
听着 我只是认为
Look, I just think you live in, like,
你是一个受欢迎的姑娘
the "hot popular girl" bubble.
生活在众人的吹捧
Where everybody either treats you
与嫉妒之中
like a princess or like an object.
可能那让你有点自恋
Maybe it makes you a little... self-absorbed or something?
你说的没错
That's fair.
但是你不觉得 你这么爱挑剔人
But do you think maybe the reason why you're
是因为你害怕
so judgy is because you're, like, afraid that
别人不会喜欢你
people aren't gonna like you,
所以你就决定先讨厌他们
so you decide not to like them first?
没有
No.
好吧 可能是这样吧
Maybe. Maybe.
好的
Okay, then.
我的意思是 你挺好的 自信一点
I'm just saying, you're a babe. Own it.
谢谢
Thanks.
我也觉得
I guess.
这游戏太恶心了 斯宾塞 离我远点
So sick of this game. Just stay out of my way, Spencer.
你干嘛老冲我发火
What are you mad at me for?
为什么冲你发火? 这不是很明显的么
Why? Are you seriously asking me that?
你害我被足球队开除
You got me kicked off the team.
然后又害得我被困在这个鬼地方
Then you got me stuck in whatever... Whatever this is.
现在你来问我为什么我们做不成朋友
And you wonder why we not friends no more.
你是不想被困在尤曼吉
This is why we're not friends anymore?
才不想跟我做朋友 我可不这么认为
You didn't wanna get stuck in Jumanji? I don't think so.
我看是因为在你眼里我不够酷
We're not friends because I'm not cool enough
不配当你的朋友
to hang out with you, so you pretended
所以你还假装不认识我
not to even know me anymore, until you needed me
等你做不了作业 才想起有我这个朋友
to do your homework because you couldn't do it yourself.
难怪你不知道
No wonder you don't know anything
西进运动是什么
about westward expansion.
你说什么 斯宾塞
Okay, you see that? You know what?
你知道么 我一点也不蠢
I'm not stupid, Spencer.
我只是让你帮我一个小忙而已
I asked you to do me one simple favor.
我让你帮忙做作业
Do my homework, so I don't
以免被足球队开除 但是你把它搞砸了
get kicked off the team, and you messed that up.
现在我连球都踢不了
Now I can't do the one thing that I'm good at,
都是拜你所赐
and it's all your fault.
我真应该狠狠揍你一顿
I should kick the shit out you right now.
你大可以试试
I'd like to see you try.
你说什么
What did you say?
噢好
Oh, okay.
我知道了
I see what's going on here.
伙伴们
Guys.
你认为你自己身高有六英尺四五英寸
You think because you... You, what, 6'4", 6'5",
重270磅 一身肌肉
270 pounds of pure muscle,
所以我就该怕你是吧
I'm supposed to be afraid of you?
你是不是这样想的
Is that what you think?
也许吧
Maybe.
我来告诉你 你还是那个
Let me tell you something.
我从七年级开始
You're still the same annoying kid
就想摆脱的烦人精
I've been trying to shake since seventh grade.
一直如此
Ain't nothing changed.
别以为有了新身体 你就了不起了
Don't let this new body get your butt whupped.
笨蛋
Dumb-ass.
- 不 -  斯宾塞
- No! -  Spencer!
斯宾塞
Spencer!
- 你杀了他 -  大冰箱 你疯了
- You killed him! -  Fridge, you lunatic!
冷静一点 他马上就会回来的
Chill out. He'll be back.
不要叫我笨蛋
Don't call me a dumb-ass.
以后别推我
Don't push me.
推你又怎样 斯宾塞
Or what, Spencer?
我会以牙还牙
Or I'll push you back.
你扇我耳光
Did you just smack me?
你敢扇我耳光
You gonna smack me?
- 冰箱 别  - 好吧 好吧
- Fridge, no. -  Yeah, yeah.
你要扇我...
Huh? You wanna smack...
不不不
Oh, no, no, no!
够了
Enough.
我们别再浪费生命了
We can't waste lives.
我们要团结
We need each other.
不管愿不愿意 我们都得齐心协力
Like it or not, we have to do this together.
你能把刚才那句话再说一遍吗
Could you say that one more time, please?
- 我们都得齐心协力 -  刚才那个深沉的语调
- We have to do this together? -  But with the smolder.
你是自己能控制的 还是自然而然就说出来了
Do you have control of that, or does that happen naturally?
自然而然就说出来了
It just happens naturally.
所以我们接下来该做什么
What are we supposed to be doing?
寻找地图上丢失的那一块
Looking for the missing map piece.
那我们为什么不问问别人呢
So we just start asking for it?
我们现在只能四处看看
No, I think we look around, scope the place out,
先摸清周围的环境 最重要的还是
but most importantly, guys,
保持谨慎
be discreet.
面包 新鲜的面包
Rations! Get your rations!
你们身上有钱吗 我都快饿死了
Does anyone have any money? I'm literally starving.
面包 新鲜的面包
Rations! Get your rations!
面包
Rations!
嘿伙伴们 要继续玩这个游戏
Guys, I think the game is trying to tell us
我们要保持体力
to keep our health up.
该吃点东西
We need to eat.
省省吧
Okay, stop doing that.
天哪 这也太好吃了吧
Oh, my God, this is so good.
我九岁开始就没吃过面包了
I haven't had bread since I was, like, 9.
真的假的
Are you serious?
不然我怎么会这么苗条
How do you think I got these abs?
让我来尝尝
Let me try some of that.
等等 这 这是什么
Wait, what... What is this?
这是我最拿手的蛋糕
That's my famous pound cake.
蛋糕
Cake?
贝瑟尼 你之前说这是面包的
Bethany, you said this was bread.
我觉得可能是太久没吃了 搞混了
It's been so long, I forgot what it tastes like.
你怎么能搞混
How do you forget what...
- 快看我 我有什么变化吗 -  没有
- What's hap... Something happening to me? - No.
- 我 我 我有没有颤抖 -  没有
-  Am I... Am I shaking? - No.
我有起疹子吗
Am I breaking out?
没有
No.
- 我皮肤还是黑色的吧 -  是的
- Am I still black? -  Yes.
是的 是的 没错
Okay. Okay, right?
我很正常 一切正常
We're fine. Everything is fine.
不不不 弱点可能是说
Yeah, no, no, no, it's okay.
我特喜欢吃蛋糕
It probably just meant that I love cake.
完全抗拒不了它的美味
That I couldn't resist it. Yeah.
嘿 一切都好
Hey, it's all good...
我的天
God!
搞什么
What the hell? Ugh!
我说过的 要保持谨慎
Like I said, important to be discreet.
你还说过我们该吃东西呢
Hey, you also said eat.
面包 新鲜的面
Rations! Get your...
你最好给我闭嘴
You better shut your ass up!
谢天谢地 勇石博士 你来了
Dr. Bravestone. Thank goodness you're here.
尤曼吉需要你
Jumanji needs you.
谢谢 很荣幸
Uh. Thanks. Good to be here.
问他关于地图的事
Ask about the missing piece.
哦对 嗨 我是贝瑟尼
Oh, right. Hi. I'm Bethany.
我的意思是 我是谢利教授
I mean... Professor Shelly, something.
我是一个地图专家
I'm a map doctor,
我现在手上有一张地图 缺了一块
and I have this map that, like, has a missing piece.
谢天谢地 勇石博士
Dr. Bravestone. Thank goodness you're here.
你来了 尤曼吉需要你
Jumanji needs you.
真没礼貌
Rude.
我们要找到缺的那块地图
We need to find the missing piece.
"所需之物 就在篮中"
What you need is in the basket.
"稍有不慎 万丈深渊"
One false move, you're in a casket.
信任彼此 请勿眨眼
Trust one another, and never blink.
寻得残片 远不止此
The missing piece is not what you think.
好吧
Oy vey.
祝你好运 强大的英雄
Good luck, mighty hero.
- 尤曼吉需要你 -  我们知道
- Jumanji needs you. -  Jumanji needs him. We know.
你说过很多遍了
You said it several times.
所以 我觉得里面可能
So thinking there's a, um...
有条蛇 或者什么其他的东西
A snake in there or something?
是的
Yep.
听起来这活适合你
Sounds like a Bravestone thing to me.
为什么听起来就适合我呢
Why would this be a Bravestone thing?
因为你是强大的英雄 你听到
You're the hero. You heard what he said.
他说的了 尤曼吉需要你 上啊
"Jumanji needs you." Now, get.
我不想做这个
I don't wanna do this!
快点吧
Just go.
黑曼巴蛇
Black mamba!
是一条黑曼巴蛇
That's a black mamba.
零点二五毫克的毒液就足以杀死一个成年人
A quarter milligram of its venom is enough to kill an adult.
如果被它咬了 会感觉嘴里有刺痛感
You'll feel a tingling in your mouth and extremities,
紧接着是发烧 呕吐及共济失调
followed by a fever, foaming at the mouth, and ataxia,
也就是肌肉失去控制
which means loss of muscle control.
- 我怎么会知道这些的 -  我们现在怎么办
- How do I know that? -  What do we do?
- 你看见里面有什么其他的东西吗 -  我没来得及看
- See anything else in there? -  I didn't have time.
- 我的天 -  好了
- Oh, my God. -  Okay.
好的 信任彼此 请勿眨眼 不要眨眼
"Trust one another and never blink." Never blink.
啊 各位 我觉得这是一个瞪眼比赛
You guys, I think it's a staring contest.
- 什么 -  你在说什么
- What? -  What are you talking about?
- 想想 请勿眨眼 -  各位 我觉得她是对的
- Think about it. "Never blink"? -  Guys, I think she's right.
夏令营的老师告诉过我们
At camp, they used to tell us
如果你碰见响尾蛇 千万不能动
if you see a rattlesnake, don't move. I think someone
我觉得得有人来盯着蛇的眼睛 不能眨眼
has to make direct eye contact and not blink.
然后斯宾塞把手伸进去
And then Spencer will reach in and grab
- 把里面的东西拿出来 -  什么 为什么 又是我
- whatever else is in there. -  What? Why me again?
- 因为你是勇石博士啊 -  好吧 我来
- Because you're Bravestone. -  Okay, fine.
那谁擅长这个瞪眼游戏
Who's good at staring and not blinking?
这个我很擅长
I'm amazing at it.
那么现在就看你的了
Then this is your moment.
加油 贝瑟尼
Come on, Bethany.
你说开始就开始
Just say when.
就现在
Now.
我们现在怎么办
What do we do?
你要拔掉它的毒牙
You gotta defang it.
我要干啥
I gotta what?
你得从它的视觉盲区
You gotta pull his mouth back
钳住它的嘴
from the blind spot to disorient it.
但是你要非常小心
But be very careful of the venom gland
别碰到它的毒腺和二级毒眼
and the exposed secondary venom duct.
然后把毒牙从头部
Then you gotta snap its teeth...
干净利落的拔出来
...out of its head.
我觉得这不是瞪眼比赛
I guess it wasn't a staring contest.
信任彼此 请勿眨眼
"Trust each other and never blink."
你们信任我
You trusted me.
你们信任我 所以我才能拔掉蛇的毒牙
You trusted me, and I defanged the snake.
我做到了 我做到了
I did it. I did that.
是的 你做到了
Yeah. Yeah, you did it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
没事
Oh, yeah. Sure.
各位
You guys?
这不像是地图上缺的那块
This does not look like a piece of a map.
缺失的部分是一只大象吗
The missing piece is an elephant?
等等 包装纸上写了些东西
Oh, wait, there's something written on the wrapping paper.
见我之时 攀登开始
"When you see me, begin the climb."
看见大象 就开始登山么
"Begin the climb?" When you see an elephant?
我拔掉了毒牙
I defanged a snake.
所以 我觉得我们下一关
So keep your eyes peeled for an elephant, I guess?
得注意一头大象
That's, like, the next level of the game?
嘿
Hey!
跑
Run!
我的天
Oh, God.
小心
Watch out!
跳过去
Jump!
- 跳 - 快快快
- Jump. -  Go, go, go!
我要警告你 我的拳头可能不太轻
I have to warn you, I think I'm a very strong puncher.
格挡
Parry.
格挡 闪避 格挡
Parry. Parry. Evade. Block.
上勾拳
Uppercut.
闪 爆头
Duck! Head smash!
打飞你
Kerpow!
闪避 格挡
Duck! Block!
打飞你
Ka-blam!
闪避 给你一拳
Evade! Punch!
朝墙扔
Wall toss!
这太疯狂了
That is insane.
我们干吧
Let's do this.
干什么
Do what?
放 放在我的背包里
Put... Put it in my backpack.
闪避 摔头
Dodge! Head slam!
送你上天
Throw through ceiling!
你好 博士
Hello, doctor.
好久不见
Been a long time.
我觉得你拿走了某些属于我的东西
I believe you have something that belongs to me.
我们只是想回家
We just wanna go home.
快走 跟我来
Come on! Come with me! Hurry!
抓住他
Get him!
快来
Come on.
下去 快
Down here. Come on. Quick!
我需要你们跟着我 然后照我说的做
I need you to follow me and do exactly as I say.
走这里
Let's move.
我的天 你们想象不到 我看到你们有多激动
Oh, my God, you guys, I am so stoked you are here.
- 是吗 -  特别激动
- You have no idea. So stoked. -  You are?
我的意思是 我看见你们在集市
I mean, I saw you guys in the bazaar,
我心里想 这不可能
and I thought to myself, "No way."
后来我想 是的 这是真的
Then I was like, yeah, that's...
靠墙站
Backs against the wall!
我的天
Oh, my goodness!
我们继续走吧
Let's keep moving.
- 小心脚步 -  你是谁
- Watch your step in here. -  Um, who are you?
你以为我们是谁
And who do you think we are?
好的 抱歉 我的错
Right. Sorry, okay, my bad.
唔 这个我们等会说
Um. Let me back up a little bit here.
你是飞行员吗 水上飞机什么的
Wait, are you the pilot? "Seaplane" somebody?
- 是的 那就是我 - 你什么意思
- Yeah, that's me. -  Wait a minute.
等等 你是那个先被选掉的角色
You're the other character that was taken.
- 所以你也是在游戏里吗 -  别踩白色的砖
- So you're in the game too? -  Stay off the white bricks...
- 什么 -  别动
- What? -  And freeze.
好险啊
So gnarly.
这游戏烂透了
This game sucks.
等等
Hup!
好了 我来拿这块木板
All right. Get this plank.
跟我走
Follow me.
当心点 掉下去就惨了
Careful. It's a horrible way to die.
我的天
Oh, God.
往那边走 很好
There you go. All right.
快
Come on.
我可以 我可以的 我刚才还拔了蛇的毒牙呢
I got it, I got it. I just defanged a snake.
尊重我一点
Give me a little respect.
好的
Okay.
- 你好 -  嗨
- Hi there. -  Hi.
快点
Come on.
无论如何 我是亚历克斯
Anyway, I'm Alex.
斯宾塞·吉尔平
Spencer Gilpin.
玛莎 大冰箱和贝瑟尼
Martha, Fridge and Bethany.
贝瑟尼 你是女孩子吗
Bethany? You're a girl?
是女人
Woman.
现实里你可能会追她的
In real life, you'd probably wanna hit that.
他们逃走了 看来有人帮助他们
They got away. Looks like they had help.
水上飞行家
Seaplane.
他一定从藏身处爬出来了
He must've crawled out of his hole.
对不起 老大
I'm sorry, boss.
这种事不会再发生了
It won't happen again.
我知道肯定不会了
I know it won't.
你在做什么
What are you making?
玛格丽特鸡尾酒 我的强项之一
Margaritas. It's actually one of my strengths.
另一项特长是开飞机 虽然 有几只人猿
That and piloting, although I did get shot down
开着战斗机 把我给打下来了
by a couple orangutans in fighter jets,
所以 可能没有特别擅长
so maybe not that great at it.
无论如何 干杯
Anyway, cheers.
- 谢谢 -  当然
- Oh. Thanks. -  Sure.
我以前从没喝过酒
I've never had alcohol before.
我也是
Me either.
- 管它呢 -  干杯
- Know what? What the hell? Woo! -  Lehayim.
- 我喝够了 -  这个不错
- And I'm done with that. -  It's good.
我能再来点吗
Can I get one more of those?
亚历克斯
Alex?
这些蜡烛是用来干嘛的
What's up with all these candles?
香茅 我的弱点之一是蚊子
Citronella. One of my weaknesses
这就有点太倒霉了
is mosquitoes, which is kind of a bummer
毕竟我要独自生活在丛林里
when you live alone in an open hut in the jungle.
他单身
He's single.
这是谁
Who's this?
谁是艾伦·帕里什
Who's Alan Parrish?
这个木屋就是他建的
He's the guy who built this place.
还有人被困在这个游戏里?
Wait, other people have been stuck here too?
是的 我是说这是艾伦·帕里什的房子 我只是暂时借住而已
Yeah. This is Alan Parrish's house. I'm just living in it.
亚历克斯 告诉我
So, Alex, tell me,
你在这游戏中待了多久
how long have you been in the game?
这很难说
Oh, it's tough to say.
这里没有时间概念
Time is kind of funny here.
但是 至少几个月吧
But a few months, at least.
- 几个月 -  什么
- A few months? -  What?
是的 我一直都过不了
Yeah, I can't seem to make it
交通工具屋
past the transportation shed.
交通工具屋 是什么
Transportation shed? What's that?
那是下一关
It's the next level.
第一次我的热气球不能起飞
First time, my hot-air balloon wouldn't even take off.
第二次就是我说的飞机被击落那一次
And then there was the whole plane thing I mentioned.
现在 我只剩最后一条命了
And once I got down to my last life,
我意识到我卡在这了
I realized I was screwed.
就是说只凭我自己 我可能永远出不去
And that I was never gonna get out of here by myself.
我必须停下来 我没有退路了 再遇到危险就死定了
Half the stuff that came at me, I had zero way to deal with.
鸡尾酒可没法杀掉黑曼巴蛇
You can't kill a black mamba with a margarita.
你肯定不行 这事得靠动物学家
You sure can't. You need a zoologist for that.
亚历克斯 我们可以互相帮助
Alex, we can help each other.
你已经在这待了很长一段时间 你很了解这个游戏了
You've been here a long time, you know the game,
我们几个有很多强项
and between us, we have a lot of strengths.
是的 我们合作的相当不错
Yeah. We're actually pretty good together.
我没有信心
I don't know, bro.
我再搞砸一次 我就会死
Okay, I mess up one more time, I'm toast.
一想到要回交通工具屋继续闯关
Totally freaks me out even thinking about
我就很害怕
going back to the transportation shed.
我不想死在尤曼吉里
I don't wanna die in Jumanji.
我们要团结一致
We just gotta stick together.
这样就能成功 我相信我们可以的
If we do that, we can win. I know we can.
我的天 你是缺失的那部分
Oh, my God. You're our missing piece.
我们要找的就是你
You were the thing we needed to find.
所以线索是
So the clue was to, what,
去集市找到缺失的部分
go to the bazaar to find the missing piece?
不是大象
It wasn't the elephant.
- 是我 -  对
- It was me. -  Yeah.
伙计们 我们一起干吧
Dudes, let's do this.
- 好 - 好
- Yeah. -  Yeah.
- 我们一起干 -  一起干
- Let's do this. -  Let's do this.
嘿 斯宾塞 你不喝那杯玛格丽特了吗
Hey, Spencer, you gonna drink that margarita?
我...你别喝了吧
I... You're done.
这酒很棒的
This is one good margarita.
就是这了 交通工具屋
There it is. The transportation shed.
里面有各种各样的交通工具
There's all sorts of vehicles inside.
我们要搞到一种 穿越峡谷
We gotta get one, get across the canyon,
然后到美洲豹神像那里
and get to the Jaguar statue.
好的 我找到交通工具屋了
Okay, I see the transportation shed,
还找到了 峡谷 但是我一直找不到那个神像
I see the canyon, but I still can't see the statue,
好奇怪啊 那个神像可是尤曼吉里最
which is weird 'cause it's the most important thing
重要的东西 而且它很大
in Jumanji and it's huge.
那只是你觉得大而已
That's what she said.
你喝醉了吧 大冰箱
You drunk, Fridge?
你瞎说什么呢？ 我才没喝醉呢
What are you talking about? I ain't drunk.
- 他已经醉了 -  我就喝了三小杯鸡尾酒
- He is drunk. -  I had three little margaritas.
别忘了 你现在的身材大概是你平时的一半
You're about half your usual size.
那又怎样 那又怎样
Whatever, whatever.
亚历克斯 我们该怎么做 我们怎么才能通过那些卫兵呢
Alex, what do we do? How do we get past these guards?
上次我一直等到他们离开
Last time, I waited till they left.
那需要花多长时间
How long did that take?
- 三周 -  噢 那也太久了 我们会死的
- Three weeks? -  Oh, we gonna die.
好的 还有别的方案吗？
Okay. Plan B.
也许还有别的门可以进去
Maybe there's another door somewhere.
但是我们得先把那些家伙支开
But we gotta distract those guys first.
我想到办法了
I've got it.
吸引男人可是我最擅长的事情了
Distracting guys is, like, the main thing I do.
他擅长玩电子游戏 而我擅长吸引男人
He plays video games, I distract guys.
贝瑟尼 我现在不想扫你的兴
Bethany, I hate to break it to you right now,
但你现在真的没有 啊 那个硬件设施
but you don't exactly have the, um, the tool kit.
- 不是我 -  什么
- Not me. -  What?
你得下去跟那些家伙搭讪
You have to go down there and flirt with those guys...
不要
No.
拖住他们 然后我们趁机溜进去
...and hold their attention while we sneak in.
不要
No!
我才不要过去跟那两个
I can't just go over there and flirt
我甚至都不认识的奇怪的 大兵搭讪呢
with some weird soldiers I don't know.
我明白 女孩 但是现在我们也没有更好的办法了
I know, but right now we don't have a better idea.
你不明白 我是真的做不到
You don't understand. I actually can't do it.
我没法和那些家伙说话
I can't talk to guys.
我会搞砸的
I'm terrible at it.
我会教你的
I can give you some pointers.
不行 对不起 啊 我们还是想想别的
No, I'm sorry. We have to come up with another plan.
办法吧 我不行 不 真的做不到
I'm not... No. Heh. Not doing that.
玛莎 你只需要引开他们的注意力
Martha, you just have to distract them long enough
给我们足够的时间溜进交通工具屋就行了
for us to get into the shed.
斯宾塞 我真的做不到 我不是
I really don't think I can, I'm not...
我真的不是那种性感美女
Like, I'm not actually some badass girl.
你瞎说 你就是个性感美女
What are you talking about? You're a total badass.
你能办到的
You could do anything.
说得真动听 斯宾塞
That's beautiful, Spencer.
我干脆现在就 帮你们安排一顿烛光晚餐得了
Why don't I set you up with a nice candlelight dinner?
你们还想不想逃出这个鬼地方了
Or do you guys wanna get the hell out of here?
好吧
All right.
教我怎么做
Show me how it's done.
开始上课
Class is in session.
- 跟我来吧 女孩 - 好的
- Come on, girl. -  Okay.
好好看着 好好学
Watch and learn.
你刚才说的烛光晚餐是什么意思
Hey, what did you mean by that candlelight-dinner thing?
- 你想问什么 -  你刚说的
- What are you talking about? -  You said it, me and Martha,
要给我和玛莎准备一顿烛光晚餐 那到底是什么意思
candlelight dinner. What does that even mean?
那个女孩喜欢你 斯宾塞
The girl is into you, Spencer.
什么
What?
听着 在跟别人调情的时候 关键就是要
Okay, in flirting situations,
让对方勾搭你
the key is making them check you out
但是你不能让对方看出来你
without letting them know
知道他们在勾搭你
that you know that they're checking you out.
装作什么都不知道 有人跟你搭讪时
You're like, "Whatever." When they try to talk to you,
你可以有三种回应
you can play it one of three ways:
装傻 超级感兴趣 讨厌
Dumb, super into it, or nasty.
具体怎么选择得看 跟你搭讪的是什么样的人
Which way you play it depends on what guy you deal with.
这既像是美梦成真 又像是噩梦降临
This is like my dream and my nightmare all at one time.
随你怎么说 我是不会介意的
I'm not gonna take that personally.
听着 头发是最重要的
Now, hair is everything.
摸一摸 捋一捋 撩一撩
Touch it. Move it. Play with it.
大幅度地抖一抖 用头发把对方迷倒
Move it around a lot. Hypnotize them with it.
像这样甩一下头发 好了 眼睛向下看
Give me a flip like that. Okay, now angle your eyes down.
好的现在 低头
Now, head down.
往上偏点儿 眼睛瞪大
Tilt up. Eyes big.
- 现在 眼睛闪光 -  闪光
- Now sparkle. -  Sparkle?
像动画里的人物那样 眼睛闪光
Like an anime character. Now sparkle.
还需要练
Needs work.
你真的觉得她喜欢我
Do you really think she likes me?
为什么我们一直在讨论这个问题
Why are we still talking about this?
我的意思是 她如果想要亲我怎么办
I mean, what if she tries to kiss me?
那你就亲回去呀 兄弟
Then you just kiss her back, man.
呃 那她要是连招呼也不打一声就
What if she tries to kiss me, like...
直接亲上来了呢
Like, without warning?
你在说什么啊 你以前亲过别人吗
What are you talking about? Haven't you ever kissed anyone?
我没有 老兄 你要让所有人都听见吗
Don't... You gonna tell the whole jungle?
嘿 伙计们 伙计们 我发现了一个侧门 就在那里
Guys, I found a side door. Over here.
- 猜猜我发现了什么 -  别 别 别 别告诉他
- Guess what I found. -  No, no, don't tell him.
好的 现在开始学习走路
Okay, let's talk about your walk.
慢慢走
Take your time.
让我迷上你走路的样子 要像一只优雅的羚羊一样
Make a meal of it. Like a gorgeous gazelle.
或者像马一样也行 脚抬高 一只脚在另一只脚前面
Or a horse. High-step it. One foot in front of the other.
走走试试 噔 噔
And bring it. Boom, boom...
不是你这样走的呀
That's not it.
啊哟
Yikes.
你可以像这样轻轻地咬嘴唇来
Anything you can do to draw attention to the lips.
吸引他们的注意力
A little nibble like this.
咬嘴唇这招特别好用 姐妹儿
A nibble goes a long way, girlfriend.
很好 走得好多了
Good. That's better.
现在微笑 别表现得那么害怕
Now smile. You look terrified.
哦 天 你真有趣
Oh, God, you're so funny.
- 你真有趣 -  哦 天那 你真有趣
- You're so funny. -  Oh, God, you're so funny.
哦 天 你真有趣
Oh, my God, you're so funny.
- 我想我找到感觉了 -  你确实找到感觉了 继续走 姐妹儿
- I think I'm getting it. -  You are getting it. Go, girl.
现在把你的嘴唇微微分开 像 像
Now, keep your lips slightly parted, like...
别这么恶心 放松
Yeah, not-not gross, just relaxed.
现在用舌头顶住上颚
Touch your tongue to the roof of your mouth.
- 像这样 -  像这样
- Like this. -  Like this?
像这样
Like this.
Like this?
我觉得你可以上场了
I think you're ready.
- 不错 -  好的
- Cool. -  Okay, flirt
我们是死是活就看这次搭讪能不能成功了
like our lives depend on it.
因为的确如此
'Cause they do.
门在那儿
Okay, there's the door.
我需要工具来 切断篱笆
We just need something to cut through the fence.
好的 大冰箱 你背包里有没有合适的工具
Okay, Fridge, you got anything like that in the backpack?
呃 当然 应该有吧
Uh, yeah, I should. What...
哇 找到了 我找到了断线钳
Here you go. I got some... Some bolt cutters.
这个工具很适合现在的情况 对吧
Does that seem like a good tool for the situation?
非常合适
Perfect, actually.
这就叫做背包的力量 宝贝
It's called backpack power, baby.
伙计们
You guys,
我觉得搭讪这招能行
I think this is gonna work.
我也这么觉得
I think so too. She's pretty fly.
她还是挺漂亮的 而那些家伙 没有见过多少人
And those guys don't meet a lot of new people.
漂亮
"Fly"?
好吧 不是辛迪 克劳馥的那种
Well, not like Cindy Crawford fly,
好看 但是在尤曼吉里应该算是好看的了
but for Jumanji, she the bomb.
好看
"The bomb"?
- 辛迪 克劳馥 -  你就这标准
- Cindy Crawford? -  That's your go-to?
我只是说 我确定
I'm just saying, I'm sure
那两个家伙肯定想泡她
they'd like to get jiggy with her.
亚历克斯
Alex.
今年是哪一年
What year do you think it is?
- 你问这个是什么意思 -  噢 不
- What do you mean? -  Oh, no.
是1996年吧
It's 1996.
你是亚历克斯 弗里克 对吗
You're Alex Vreeke, aren't you?
是的 我是
Yeah, that's right.
等等 你是说怪房子的那个?
Wait a minute, you mean Freak House?
等等 伙计 你们在说什么啊
Wait, what are you... What are you guys talking about?
你们是怎么认识我的
How do you know me?
亚历克斯 我实在是不知道该怎么说这件事
Alex, I don't know how to tell you this...
你已经在这个游戏里呆了二十年了
You've been in this game for 20 years.
我本来想委婉点告诉你的
That's probably not how I would've done it.
什么
What?
不 你们是在逗我玩呢 对吧
No. You guys are messing with me, right?
不 我们没有 亚历克斯 弗里克
No, we're not. Alex Vreeke.
布兰特福德镇上的的每一个人都知道你
Everybody in Brantford knows about you.
你就是那个二十年前
You're the kid that disappeared.
失踪的那个孩子
Twenty years ago.
二十年
Twenty years?
二十年了 伙计
Twenty years, man.
我不知道该怎么跟你说 但是
I don't even know how to say this, but
辛迪 克劳馥现在大概有50岁了
Cindy Crawford, dude, she's like 50 years old.
- 但还是很靓 -  嗯
- But still fly. -  Eh.
好吧
Wait...
她到了
There she is.
嘿
Hey.
我们会带你出去的
We're gonna get you home.
好
Yeah.
她的屁股怎么了
The hell is going on with her butt?
贝瑟尼 你是怎么教她的
Bethany, what did you tell her to do?
她的脚难道扭伤了吗
Did she twist her ankle, maybe, or...
她以前从来没有跟别人 搭过讪 别挑刺儿了
She's never flirted before. Give her a break.
你好 小姑娘
Hello, little lady.
你一个人来这儿干什么
What are you doing out here all alone?
嗨 伙计们
Hey, you guys.
我好像迷路了
I seem to be lost.
你们能帮帮我吗
Can you guys help me?
你好 小姑娘
Hello, little lady.
你一个人来这里干什么
What are you doing out here all alone?
啊哈哈哈哈 你们真是太有趣了
You guys are so interesting and funny.
她在干什么呀
What's she doing?
她头发里有虫子吗
What, she got a bug in her hair?
她把我教她的东西全都忘记了
She's forgotten all of our training.
我们走吧
Let's go.
等等 我 呃
Wait! I... I... I have to tell you
我得给你们讲讲我以前读过的一本书
about this book that I've been reading.
是关于微生物学的
About microbiology.
那可是我最喜欢的生物学分支
Which is one of my favorite biologies.
你好 小姑娘
Hello, little lady.
你一个人来这儿干什么
What are you doing out here all alone?
你可是个性感美女
You are a badass.
嗨
Hey.
你们两个想跳舞吗
You guys like to dance?
我们穿过来了
Oh, yeah, there we go.
哪一个 哪一个 哪一个
Which one, which one, which one?
我讨厌这个地方
I hate this place.
噢 她很擅长战舞
Her strength is dance fighting.
亚历克斯 你怎么想 你觉得接下来我们该怎么办
Alex, what do you think, huh? What's the move?
- 什么 -  我们该拿什么 拿哪一个
- What? -  What do we take? Which one?
我不知道 我不知道 好吗 伙计
I don't know, man, okay?
- 我都说了 我 -  我们必须要起飞了
- I told you, I... -  We gotta fly.
对吧 选直升机吧 我们得起飞了
The helicopter? We gotta fly.
我都说了我不知道
I told you I don't know.
她在痛揍他们
She's kicking their ass.
她真棒
That's our girl.
太棒了
Yes, queen!
她快把他们打趴下了
She is destroying them.
- 太厉害了 姐妹儿 - 没错
- You go, girl! -  Yeah.
哇哦
Woo! Woo-hoo!
厉害 厉害
Go, go!
你是我的英雄
Yes! Yes! You're my hero.
- 我们必须要走了 -  你应该给我传授一下
- We gotta go. -  You should give me
如何揍人的
lessons in kicking ass.
姐妹儿抱一个
Give me a hug.
- 哦 我的天 -  你做到了
- Oh, my God. -  You did it.
-  我做到了 - 耶 姐妹儿 抱一个吧
- I did. -  Yeah, give me a hug, girlfriend.
这真是个伟大的时刻但是我们没时间庆祝了
As great of a moment as that is, we ain't got the time.
- 各位 行了 - 他们要来了
- Yeah. - They coming.
那些骑摩托的 怪人要来了
The motorcycle freaks is coming.
飞行员快去开飞机 我们得起飞了伙计
Seaplane! We got to fly, man.
不 我做不到 好吗
Nope. I can't do it.
我都告诉过你们了 我开不好飞机
Okay? I told you, I'm not a good pilot.
要不我们开校车走吧
Maybe we should take the school bus.
什么 开着那辆小破车怎么能跑得过那群怪物
We can't outrun no motorcycle on no damn bus!
你已经试过飞机和热气球了
You picked the plane and hot-air balloon.
说不定你就该开直升机呢
Maybe pick the helicopter.
不行 我做不到 我不想死
No, I can't do it. Okay? I don't wanna die.
我有点吓坏了
I'm freaking out a little bit.
好吧 那我来开
Fine. I'll do it.
能有多难开呢 不就是个直升机
How hard can it be? It's a helicopter.
你按个按钮
You... You press a button, the...
这东西开始转
They gonna spin. Okay.
嗯 接着拉那个控制杆
Then after that, I got my... The... The lever.
然后 就能开着
That's how... That's how you getting
直升机前后移动了
the forward-backward action.
只要飞到天上 我应该就会开了
Once we in the air, I'mma be all right.
我只要 对了
This, I just gotta get...
有没有凳子能让我上去
'Cause it ain't got no step stool, so...
让我看看 我也可以就这么进去
Let me see something. I can probably just...
就是要小心点
Get in, but be careful.
- 不 你醉了 -  不行 那可不行
- No, you're drunk. -  No way. Nuh-uh.
冰箱 你醉了 把钥匙给他
Fridge, you're drunk. Give me the keys.
- 我… - 亚历克斯 亚历克斯
- I'm? -  Alex. Alex.
既然我都能打败外面那些人
If I can fight those guys,
你就能开直升机 我知道你可以的
you can fly this helicopter. I know you can.
拜托
Come on.
亚历克斯
Alex.
我们需要你
This is where we need you.
要知道 你是缺的那一块啊
Remember, you're the missing piece.
水上飞行家 麦克多诺 特来报到
Seaplane McDonough reporting for duty.
我们走吧
Let's go, people.
哇哦
Whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- 怎么回事 -  什么东西坏了
- What's wrong? -  Something's broken!
- 什么 - 什么意思
- What? -  What do you mean?
稳住
Hang on!
天啊 我们要死了
Oh, my God, we're about to die!
我们要死了
We're about to die!
- 我的老天 -  高度提不起来
- Oh, my God! -  It won't go up!
- 什么 -  你什么意思
- What? -  What do you mean?
总距控制出故障了
The collective is busted.
- 什么东西 -  它在上面 控制直升机
- What? -  It controls the plate up there,
也就是控制使旋翼倾斜 调整桨距
which tilts the rotors and controls the pitch.
这样直升机才能升降
It's how we go up and down.
嘿 各位
You guys?
- 那可不是好兆头 -  不可能是好事情
- That can't be good. -  It's no way that's good news.
一群白化犀牛
Albino rhinos!
他们是尤曼吉本地生物
They're indigenous to Jumanji.
庞大 苍白 恐怖 愚蠢
They're huge, white, scary, and stupid,
- 还吃人 -  不
- and they eat people. -  No.
他们更近了
They're getting close!
我的胃开始有些不舒服了
My stomach's starting to bother me a bit.
- 往上飞啊 -  我飞不上去
- Go up! -  I can't go up!
我可能真是喝多了
I think I had too many margaritas.
我们怎么办
You guys, what are we gonna do?
我去修好直升机
I'll fix the helicopter.
- 行 -  告诉我怎么做
- Yes! -  Tell me what to do.
你要把斜板控制杆
You gotta connect the flight-control rod
接到旋翼下面的网格板上
to the mesh plate under the rotors.
斜板控制杆 网格板 在旋翼下面
Flight-control rod, mesh plate, under the rotors.
- 什么 -  我马上回来
- Wait, what? -  I'll be right back.
- 斯宾塞 你要去哪 -  赶紧的
- Spencer, where are you going? -  Hurry up.
- 小心些 -  别乱来 快快快
- Be careful! -  No, no, just hurry up!
我只要站在这上面
All right, just gonna stand on this thingy,
靠近这些致命的直升机桨叶 好了
pull myself up towards these deadly helicopter blades. Okay.
看到网格板了
There's the mesh plate.
这是控制杆
Here's that rod thingy.
- 斯宾塞 喔 -  快点 亚历克斯
- Spencer! -  Speed it up, Alex!
斯宾塞
Spencer!
快点 修好它
Hurry! Come on, fix it!
- 我的天啊 -  快来不及了
- Oh, my God! -  Running out of time!
- 快修好 -  不不不
- Fix it, please! -  No, no, no.
成了
Got it!
我们成功了 我还以为我们要死了呢
We made it! You did it! I thought we were gonna die.
- 耶 -  太好了
- Oh. -  Yes!
- 不错 -  谢谢你
- Nice! -  Thank you.
- 谢谢各位 -  你做到了 真是太惊险了
- Thank you, guys. -  You did it. That was scary.
糟了
Oops.
怎么了
What?
宝石掉下去了
I dropped the jewel.
什么
What?
你把宝石丢了
You dropped the jewel?
我趴在那
I leaned over,
我以为我要吐的 结果没吐
thought I had to puke, and I didn't.
然后它就从我包里掉出去了
It came out of my backpack.
- 我们需要那个该死的宝石 -  我知道
- We need the freaking jewel! -  I know.
这是最最最令人抓狂的 因为我知道我们需要它
That's-that's-that's the crazy part 'cause I know we need it.
所以 我们遇到大麻烦了 大麻烦
So we're in a pickle. We're in a pickle.
亚历克斯 掉头回去 我们得把它拿回来
Turn around. We gotta go get it.
是的 就绕个弯 去找找
Yeah, let's loop around. Look for it.
大家都睁大眼睛好好找找
Everybody open your eyes.
我们一起把宝石找回来
Let's all look for it as a group.
在那儿 我看见了
There! I see it!
它们在干嘛
What are they doing?
它们好像在守护那颗宝石
It's like they're protecting it or something.
- 那我们怎么办 - 我不知道
- How are we gonna do this? -  I don't know.
你要去拿宝石 是的吧
Well, you gotta go get it, right, buddy?
你需要什么 要回旋镖吗
What do you need? Your boomerang?
还是剪刀
Maybe some scissors?
管钳子 或者鞋带
A pipe wrench? Some shoelaces?
我是你的助手 你需要什么我就能帮你弄到什么
I'm your valet. Whatever you need, I can get it for you.
你开口就行
Okay? You just say the word.
- 什么 -  抱歉 兄弟
- What? -  I'm sorry, buddy.
抱歉什么
Sorry for what?
不
No.
我们掉头
Turn us around.
不
No!
我的天
Oh, my God!
- 不 - 亚历克斯 准备侧着飞
- No! -  Alex, get ready to roll us to the side.
什么
What?
我叫你的时候 右翻九十度
When I tell you, roll 90 degrees to the right.
就现在 翻
Now!
混蛋 你居然把我从直升机推下去
You pushed me out the helicopter, jackass!
哇哦
Oh, wow!
- 斯宾塞 你太棒了 -  谢啦
- Spencer, you're amazing. -  Thank you.
你是个出色的飞行员 亚历克斯
You are a killer pilot, Alex.
- 谢啦 -  斯宾塞
- Thanks. -  You too, Spencer,
- 你也是 你太棒了 -  谢谢
- you were incredible! -  Thank you...
- 嘿 - 但是是他比较厉害
- Hey! -  ...but he was amazing, our pilot.
- 你很棒 -  不好意思
- Excuse me. -  You killed it.
不好意思
Excuse me.
Excuse me!
我才是那个当诱饵的人
I'm the one that was a human sacrifice.
你们不知道那些犀牛底下都长了什么
You don't know what's on the underside of those rhinos.
你们绝对不想知道
And you don't wanna know.
我可都看见了
I've seen a lot of things.
甚至面对面感受了一下
Felt them on my face too.
我这辈子都忘不掉那些东西了
Things that I will never be able to erase from memory.
对你们来说还好笑了是吧
Oh, that's funny to you guys.
继续 随便笑
Go ahead, laugh it up. Get it out.
二十年了
Guys, I've been trying to get across
我一直在设法穿越这片峡谷
this canyon for, like, 20 years, okay?
你们知道它有多大吗
Do you realize how huge this is?
是蚊子
Mosquito.
不不不 亚历克斯
No, no, no! Alex, no, no, no!
- 亚历克斯 - 亚历克斯 不不不
- Alex. -  Alex, no, no.
亚历克斯
Alex?
亚历克斯 说话 看我
Alex, talk to me. Wake up. Here we go.
他要死了
Alex? He's dying.
不 我们不能让他死 我们离成功都这么近了
No, we can't let him die. We're too close!
有人会心肺复苏吗
Does anyone know how to do CPR?
我会 先按他胸口三下 然后人工呼吸
Yeah, start with three chest compressions and mouth-to-mouth.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
怎么人工呼吸
How do I do this?
捏住他的鼻子 打开他的嘴
Okay, pinch his nose, open his mouth,
- 完全封住 - 好的
- full lip-lock. -  Okay.
呼吸一下 两下 然后重复
Ah, one breath, two breaths, then repeat.
拜托 亚历克斯
Come on, Alex.
贝瑟尼 停下 你的纹身
Bethany, stop. Your tattoo.
看上去你这是把你的一条命给他
It looks like you're giving him one of your lives.
我觉得没关系
I'm okay with that.
要是你自己需要它呢
What if you need it for yourself?
我希望亚历克斯也能回家
I want Alex to come home too.
- 发生了什么 - 亚历克斯
- What happened? -  Alex,
贝瑟尼把她的一条命给你了
Bethany gave you one of her lives.
贝瑟尼 你还好吗
Bethany, you okay?
应该吧
I think so.
贝瑟尼 真的吗
Bethany, is that true?
你给了我一条命
You gave me one of your lives?
我是说 当然了
I mean, yeah, of course.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你在看什么呢
What? What are you looking at?
你有点状况
You got a situation.
我的天啊 这些东西真是疯了
Oh, my God, these things are crazy.
二十年了吗
Twenty years, huh?
是的
Yeah, I guess so.
你知道吗
You know,
我一直在想我可怜的父母
I just keep thinking about my poor parents.
想他们都经历了什么
And what they must've been through.
而且都是因为我太害怕了
And why, because I was sitting in my hideout,
所以一直躲着 不去结束游戏
too afraid to finish the game?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
这些话对你来说太沉重了 我只是
I don't mean to lay this on you. I'm just...
我觉得和你很容易沟通
You're really easy to talk to.
我理解
No, I get it. I mean, sometimes
我是说 有时候 你会太关注自己的事
it's easy to get so focused on your own stuff
都忘记了别人也有别人的烦恼
that you forget other people have problems too.
这话很深刻
That's really deep.
谢了 我感觉自从我手机丢了之后
Thanks. I feel like ever since I lost my phone,
我的其他感官变得灵敏了
my other senses have kind of heightened.
手机在未来都成了新的感官了吗
Does "phone" mean something different in the future?
你呢 亚历克斯 你是怎样的
What about you, Alex? What are you like?
现实世界里 你是什么性格
In the real world. What's your vibe?
完全是个重金属迷
Full-on metalhead.
是一个鼓手 和我爸一样
A drummer, like my dad.
嘿
Hey.
- 嘿 -  你在干嘛
- Hey. -  What are you doing?
我 呃 我就是把水壶灌满
I, uh, I was just filling these up.
- 挺好的 -  嗯
- Cool. -  Yeah.
我很高兴你在这 我 呃
I'm glad you're here. I, uh, ahem...
- 我有话要跟你说 - 什么
- I have something to tell you. -  Yeah?
我想现在就告诉你
And I wanna tell you now,
免得以后有机会了
just in case the next time
我又不敢了
that we talk I'm no longer brave.
我喜欢你 玛莎
I like you, Martha.
我喜欢 就是喜欢你
I, like, like you.
就是 我对你着迷
Like, I'm fully into you.
- 是吗 -  是的
- You are? -  I am.
我一直都是 大概从
And I have been
七年级就开始喜欢你了
since, like, the seventh grade.
真的吗
Really?
哇 这种事情从来没发生过在我身上
Wowza. I don't think this has ever happened before.
- 你是什么意思 -  呃 我是说
- What do you mean? -  Oh, I mean, like, I don't think
我是说我从没想过还会有人喜欢我 我不敢相信我在这么做
anyone's ever liked me that I... I can't believe I'm doing this.
我从没告诉过别人我...
I never tell anyone how I fe...
我也喜欢你 斯宾塞
I'm into you too, Spencer.
- 你喜欢我 -  是的
- You are? -  Yes. Yes! Heh, heh!
真的 你又聪明又温柔又帅气
God, you're smart and sweet and cute.
嗯 我真的很喜欢你
Yeah, I'm pretty into you.
等等 你确定那不是因为 因为这些肌肉
Wait. Are you sure it's not because of, like, all of...
什么 不不 我可不喜欢这样的肌肉男
What? Oh, my God, no, no.
我喜欢呆子
That is not my type. I'm into nerds.
真的吗
Really?
我就是呆子
I'm a nerd.
- 那真是 那真是糟糕 -  我从没有亲过谁
- That was... I was so awful. -  I've never kissed anyone.
- 你没 -  没有过 那是我的初吻
- You've never... -  Never. That was the first time.
- 我没有过 -  你没有过
- I have never. -  Oh, you haven't?
- 没有 -  啊 那挺好的
- No. -  Okay. Cool.
看不出来吧
You can't tell, right?
别吧 嘿
Come on. Hey!
我看不下去了 摆脱 别在今天
I don't wanna see that. I don't, not today.
你们在这互相告白的时候
While you're down here professing your love
我找到了美洲豹神像
for one another, I found the Jaguar.
走吧 受不了 呕
Let's go. God! Ugh!
- 就是它了 -  就是它了
- There it is. -  There it is.
我们最好行动起来
We'd better get walking.
我们就顺着这条路走
I think we just follow this path.
不 不可能这么简单
No. It can't be that easy.
守护者
"The Defenders."
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
只有一种办法能找出答案
There's only one way to find out.
冰箱
Fridge,
把宝石给我
give me the jewel.
斯宾塞
Spencer.
有事情要发生
Something's about to happen.
我讨厌那些鼓点
I hate those drums.
等等 你要直接走进去吗
What, you're just gonna walk in there?
不
No.
游戏想要我们直接走进去 顺着这条路走
That's what the game wants us to do. Follow the path.
这是个陷阱
It's a trap.
看到大象时
"When you see the elephant...
攀登开始
begin the climb."
我走树上过去
I'll go through the trees.
- 爬树 -  是的
- The trees? -  Yeah.
你觉得那句话就是这个意思吗
Do you think that's what that means?
肯定是
That must be it.
就该这么做
That's the move.
这是游戏的最后一关
This is the final level of the game.
而且我很确定这是要勇石博士做的事情
And I'm pretty sure this is a Bravestone thing.
他刚刚是不是管他自己叫勇石博士
Did he just refer to himself in the third person?
嗯 反正都是叫他
Um, fourth person, I think.
他怎么做到的
How does he do that?
攀爬是他的强项
Climbing is one of his strengths.
啊 我懂了
Oh. Gotcha.
蛋糕使我爆炸
Cake makes me explode.
- 不 -  我的天啊
- No! Spencer! -  Oh, my God!
斯宾塞
Spencer!
斯宾塞 天啊 是黑豹
Oh, my God, you guys. Panthers.
不是
No.
是美洲豹
Those are jaguars.
斯宾塞
Spencer!
天啊 你还好吗
Oh, my God. Are you okay?
还好 我想
Yeah. I think so.
宝石还在你那吧
You still have the jewel, right?
- 嗯 -  谢天谢地
- I got it. -  Oh, thank God.
发生什么事了
Hey, what happened?
我不想讨论那件事
I don't wanna talk about it.
行 我们得订个新计划了
Okay, we need a new plan.
- 嗯 -  好
- Yeah. -  Right.
- 肯定的 -  斯宾塞 有什么想法吗
- Totally. -  Spencer, any ideas?
我能和你谈一下吗
Can I speak with you for a minute?
现在吗
Now?
怎么了
What's going on?
我做不到
I can't do this.
- 你在说什么 -  我就是做不到
- What are you talking about? -  I can't do this.
我不开玩笑 我不是什么冒险家
Okay, who am I kidding? I'm not some adventurer.
我根本不勇敢
I'm not actually brave.
斯宾塞 你之前还吊在直升机外面呢
Spencer, I just saw you hanging out of a helicopter.
有好几条命时 勇敢不是难事
It's a lot easier to be brave when you have lives to spare.
如果你只有一条命
It's a lot harder...
那可就困难得多了
when you only have one life.
我们从来都只有一条命 兄弟
We-we always only have one life, man.
是的 生命就是只有一次 就是这样
Okay? That's... That's all we get. That's how it works.
问题是 你想怎么度过这一生
The question is, is how are you gonna live it?
你想成为怎样的人
Which guy are you gonna decide to be?
我刚是引用了校长的话吗
Did I just quote our principal?
这游戏把我怎么了
What the hell is this game doing to me? I gotta get out of here.
我得离开这
Look.
听着 我们能做到的
We can do this, man.
我们能一起做到
We can do it together.
- 一起 -  一起
- Together. -  Together.
你是个很好的朋友 冰箱
You're a good friend, Fridge.
好
All right.
我不懂电子游戏
Okay. I don't know video games,
但是我懂橄榄球
but what I do know is football.
外面那些狮子和吃人的大猫
Now, those lightning-fast, man-eating cats out there?
就相当于后卫
They're the Defenders.
也就是说我们要发动一轮猛攻
Which means we gotta run one hell of an offense.
大家注意
You guys.
我们得赶紧走
We gotta go.
我们这么做
All right. Here's what we're gonna do.
我们分头行动
We're gonna fan out and run a play that I call:
来一次冰箱之双反向传球
"The Double Reverse Refrigerator."
贝瑟尼 你去左边
Bethany, you go up the left side.
我去右边
I'll go up the right.
亚历克斯 你引开对方的防守
Alex, you'll draw the defense,
然后斯宾塞就能走中路
so Spencer can go up the middle.
- 我和斯宾塞一起去 - 不
- I'll go with Spencer. -  No.
需要你做另一件事
There's something else we need you to do.
你们想跳舞吗
You guys like to dance?
嘿 我在这
Hey! Over here!
来抓我啊
Come and get me!
- 谢谢 -  没事
- Thanks. -  Sure.
去神像那 快
Get to the statue. Go!
哦天
Oh, no! I...
我的天
Oh, man. Okay.
保持冷静 别慌
Stay calm, don't panic.
不许动
Stop!
是大象就怕耗子
It's the elephant and the mouse.
你好啊
What's up?
我是耗子芬巴
Mouse Finbar.
动物学家
Zoologist.
Zoologist and...
而且 我包里有家伙呢
And backpack guy.
把宝石给我 不然你的朋友就得死
Give me the jewel, or your friend dies.
- 不要给他 -  闭嘴
- Don't give it to him! -  Quiet!
住手
Stop!
我代替他做人质 行吗
Take me instead, okay?
把宝石给我
Give me the jewel.
我不能给你
I can't do that.
五
Five.
- 四 三 -  我不能给你宝石
- Four, three... -  I can't give you the jewel.
- 斯宾塞 - 二
- Spencer. -  Two!
因为它根本不在我这
Because I don't have it!
动物学家在此
Zoology, bitch!
不 不 不 不
No, no, no! Don't...
你这混蛋
Douche bag! You suck!
- 是大象 -  攀爬开始
- Elephant. -  "Begin the climb."
别伤害她
Leave her alone!
你先上去 我去把宝石拿回来给你
Get up there, I'll get the jewel to you.
- 玛莎 -  相信我 我会拿到的
- Martha. -  Trust me.
- 好 -  去吧
- I'll get it to you. Go. -  Okay.
去吧 玛莎
Go, Martha!
亚历克斯
Alex!
给我宝石
I'll take that.
游戏结束
Game over.
我看不见得
I don't think so.
毒液是我的弱点
Venom's my weakness.
快啊 斯宾塞
Go, Spencer.
不
No.
耶
Yeah!
- 哇哦 -  太好了
- Wow! -  Yeah.
大喊一声尤曼吉
"Call out its name."
Call out its name!
各位 大家一起喊尤曼吉
Call out its name, everyone!
尤曼吉
Jumanji!
- 我觉得我们成功了 -  我们通关了
- I think we did it. -  I think we won.
我们做到了
I think we did.
快看 是奈吉尔
Guys, it's Nigel.
奈吉尔
Nigel.
做得好 勇敢的冒险者们
Well done, intrepid adventurers!
你们解除了诅咒
You lifted the curse!
我代表尤曼吉感谢你们
All of Jumanji thanks you.
你们的任务完成了
Your work here is done.
真是遗憾 我们要告别了
So, sadly, this is where we part.
水上飞机家 麦克多诺
Seaplane McDonough,
让我和你握个手道别吧
let me shake your hand.
亚历克斯
Alex.
再见 奥布伦教授
Adieu, Professor Oberon.
再见
Later, dude.
我会最想念你 小耗子
I'll miss you the most, my little Mouse.
赶紧让我离开这里
Get me the hell out of here.
再见了 铁拳萝比
Farewell, Ruby Roundhouse.
等一下
Wait.
要是我们不回去呢
What if we didn't go back?
我只是
I just...
我喜欢像这样 和你在一起
I like being like this. With you.
那 那我们就这样
Then let's be like this,
每天都在一起
every day.
先回家吧
Just come home.
勇石博士
Dr. Bravestone.
奈吉尔 我准备好回家了
Nigel, I'm ready to go home.
再见 我的好兄弟
Farewell, my good man.
再见了 勇石博士
See you later, Bravestone.
哦天
Oh, my God.
太好了 我回来了
Yes, yes, yes! Yes, yes! I'm back, baby!
我再也不会嫌弃自己的身材了
I will never complain about my body ever again.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
我想死你了
Oh, I missed you.
亚历克斯在哪
Where's Alex?
等等 看那儿
Wait, look.
是鬼屋么
Freak House?
你们觉得
Do you think...
那说明 也许
That means, maybe...
- 爷爷 -  嘿
- Grandpa! -  Hey!
过来 过来 孙女
Come here. Come here. Oh, that's my girl.
- 嗨 -  见到你真好
- Hi! -  So good to see you.
来吧 来跟奶奶打个招呼
Come on. Come on and say hi to Grandma.
- 亚历克斯 -  爸 你有时间的话
- Alex? -  Hey, Dad, when you get a sec,
- 可以帮我们一下吗 -  当然
- could you give us a hand? -  Yeah.
- 还不错啊 -  是啊
- Yeah, it's not too bad. -  Yeah.
爸 等我一下行吗
Hey, Dad, will you give me a second?
- 啊 当然 -  我马上回来
- Oh, yeah, sure. -  I'll be right back.
贝瑟尼
Bethany?
- 斯宾塞 -  是我
- Spencer? -  Yeah.
铁拳萝比
Ruby Roundhouse?
你确实壮的像个冰箱了
And that would make you Fridge.
见到你们大家
I'm stoked to see you.
真的太开心了
All of you.
- 你回来了 -  是的 我回来了
- You made it back. -  Yeah, I did.
我回到了开始游戏的那年
It spit me out right where I started, so...
1996年
1996.
那你父母 你的房子
And your parents and your house?
是啊 都挺好的
Yeah, they... All good, bro.
你现在是成年人了
You're an adult now.
你还有了个家庭
You have a family.
是的
I do, yeah.
这是安迪
This is Andy.
我还有个女儿
And then my daughter...
我女儿的名字 叫贝瑟尼
My daughter's name is Bethany.
用我救命恩人名字取的
We named her after the girl who saved my life.
真开心啊
So stoked. Heh.
哟
Yo.
你想背着包徒步旅行
You wanna go backpacking?
去野外生存
Like, in nature?
是的 去一个特别美的地方
Yeah, but, like, somewhere, like, really amazing.
明年暑假 你觉得怎么样
Next summer? What do you think?
- 你没病吧 - 嘿
- Are you okay? -  Hey.
我一会来找你
Oh, um, I'll catch you later.
我们下课见吧
I'll see you after class?
- 嘿 -  你好
- Hey! -  Hello.
- 嘿 -  所以 最近有什么
- Hey. -  So, uh, anything...
有趣的事么
interesting happen lately?
没 我是想不出来什么
No, I can't think of anything.
好吧
Yeah. Heh.
你们和玛莎有联系吗
Have you guys talked to Martha?
这周末我和她发短信来着
Oh, I was texting her this weekend.
你跟她聊过了吗
Have you talked to her?
看 她来了
Hey. There she is.
去追她吧 勇石博士
Go get that girl, Dr. Bravestone.
嗨
Hi.
- 嗨 -  我很想
- Hi. -  I really...
- 我真的很想给你打电话的 -  我理解
- I really wanted to call you. -  I get it.
但我不知道 我不知道为什么我没打
Sorry, I don't know why I didn't call.
就是从游戏出来了之后感觉很怪
It's weird being out and,
也说不清到底发生了什么
not, like, knowing, like, what's going on and...
怎么了
What?
深沉凝视
Smoldering.